<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<referencegroup anchor="STD19" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/std19">
<!-- reference.RFC.1001.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC1001' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc1001'>
<front>
<title>Protocol standard for a NetBIOS service on a TCP/UDP transport: Concepts and methods</title>
<author><organization>NetBIOS Working Group in the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</organization></author>
<author><organization>Internet Activities Board</organization></author>
<author><organization>End-to-End Services Task Force</organization></author>
<date year='1987' month='March' />
<abstract><t>This RFC defines a proposed standard protocol to support NetBIOS services in a TCP/IP environment.  Both local network and internet operation are supported.  Various node types are defined to accommodate local and internet topologies and to allow operation with or without the use of IP broadcast.  This RFC describes the NetBIOS-over-TCP protocols in a general manner, emphasizing the underlying ideas and techniques. Detailed specifications are found in a companion RFC, &quot;Protocol Standard For a NetBIOS Service on a TCP/UDP Transport: Detailed Specifications&quot;.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='19'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='1001'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC1001'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.1002.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC1002' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc1002'>
<front>
<title>Protocol standard for a NetBIOS service on a TCP/UDP transport: Detailed specifications</title>
<author><organization>NetBIOS Working Group in the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</organization></author>
<author><organization>Internet Activities Board</organization></author>
<author><organization>End-to-End Services Task Force</organization></author>
<date year='1987' month='March' />
<abstract><t>This RFC defines a proposed standard protocol to support NetBIOS services in a TCP/IP environment.  Both local network and internet operation are supported.  Various node types are defined to accommodate local and internet topologies and to allow operation with or without the use of IP broadcast.  This RFC gives the detailed specifications of the netBIOS-over-TCP packets, protocols, and defined constants and variables.  A more general overview is found in a companion RFC, &quot;Protocol Standard For NetBIOS Service on TCP/UDP Transport: Concepts and Methods&quot;.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='19'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='1002'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC1002'/>
</reference>
</referencegroup>
