<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<referencegroup anchor="BCP156" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/bcp156">
<!-- reference.RFC.6056.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC6056' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6056'>
<front>
<title>Recommendations for Transport-Protocol Port Randomization</title>
<author initials='M.' surname='Larsen' fullname='M. Larsen'><organization /></author>
<author initials='F.' surname='Gont' fullname='F. Gont'><organization /></author>
<date year='2011' month='January' />
<abstract><t>During the last few years, awareness has been raised about a number of &quot;blind&quot; attacks that can be performed against the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and similar protocols.  The consequences of these attacks range from throughput reduction to broken connections or data corruption.  These attacks rely on the attacker's ability to guess or know the five-tuple (Protocol, Source Address, Destination Address, Source Port, Destination Port) that identifies the transport protocol instance to be attacked.  This document describes a number of simple and efficient methods for the selection of the client port number, such that the possibility of an attacker guessing the exact value is reduced.  While this is not a replacement for cryptographic methods for protecting the transport-protocol instance, the aforementioned port selection algorithms provide improved security with very little effort and without any key management overhead.  The algorithms described in this document are local policies that may be incrementally deployed and that do not violate the specifications of any of the transport protocols that may benefit from them, such as TCP, UDP, UDP-lite, Stream Control Transmission Protocol (SCTP), Datagram Congestion Control Protocol (DCCP), and RTP (provided that the RTP application explicitly signals the RTP and RTCP port numbers).  This memo documents an Internet Best Current Practice.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='156'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='6056'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC6056'/>
</reference>
</referencegroup>
