<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<referencegroup anchor="STD69" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/std69">
<!-- reference.RFC.5730.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC5730' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5730'>
<front>
<title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP)</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Hollenbeck' fullname='S. Hollenbeck'><organization /></author>
<date year='2009' month='August' />
<abstract><t>This document describes an application-layer client-server protocol for the provisioning and management of objects stored in a shared central repository.  Specified in XML, the protocol defines generic object management operations and an extensible framework that maps protocol operations to objects.  This document includes a protocol specification, an object mapping template, and an XML media type registration.  This document obsoletes RFC 4930.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='69'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='5730'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC5730'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.5731.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC5731' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5731'>
<front>
<title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) Domain Name Mapping</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Hollenbeck' fullname='S. Hollenbeck'><organization /></author>
<date year='2009' month='August' />
<abstract><t>This document describes an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) mapping for the provisioning and management of Internet domain names stored in a shared central repository.  Specified in XML, the mapping defines EPP command syntax and semantics as applied to domain names. This document obsoletes RFC 4931.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='69'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='5731'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC5731'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.5732.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC5732' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5732'>
<front>
<title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) Host Mapping</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Hollenbeck' fullname='S. Hollenbeck'><organization /></author>
<date year='2009' month='August' />
<abstract><t>This document describes an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) mapping for the provisioning and management of Internet host names stored in a shared central repository.  Specified in XML, the mapping defines EPP command syntax and semantics as applied to host names. This document obsoletes RFC 4932.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='69'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='5732'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC5732'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.5733.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC5733' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5733'>
<front>
<title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) Contact Mapping</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Hollenbeck' fullname='S. Hollenbeck'><organization /></author>
<date year='2009' month='August' />
<abstract><t>This document describes an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) mapping for the provisioning and management of individual or organizational social information identifiers (known as &quot;contacts&quot;) stored in a shared central repository.  Specified in Extensible Markup Language (XML), the mapping defines EPP command syntax and semantics as applied to contacts.  This document obsoletes RFC 4933.   [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='69'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='5733'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC5733'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.5734.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC5734' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5734'>
<front>
<title>Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) Transport over TCP</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Hollenbeck' fullname='S. Hollenbeck'><organization /></author>
<date year='2009' month='August' />
<abstract><t>This document describes how an Extensible Provisioning Protocol (EPP) session is mapped onto a single Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) connection.  This mapping requires use of the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol to protect information exchanged between an EPP client and an EPP server.  This document obsoletes RFC 4934.  [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='STD' value='69'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='5734'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC5734'/>
</reference>
</referencegroup>
