<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<referencegroup anchor="BCP101" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/bcp101">
<!-- reference.RFC.4071.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC4071' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc4071'>
<front>
<title>Structure of the IETF Administrative Support Activity (IASA)</title>
<author initials='R.' surname='Austein' fullname='R. Austein' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='B.' surname='Wijnen' fullname='B. Wijnen' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<date year='2005' month='April' />
<abstract><t>This document describes the structure of the IETF Administrative Support Activity (IASA) as an activity housed within the Internet Society (ISOC).  It defines the roles and responsibilities of the IETF Administrative Oversight Committee (IAOC), the IETF Administrative Director (IAD), and ISOC in the fiscal and administrative support of the IETF standards process.  It also defines the membership and selection rules for the IAOC.  This document specifies an Internet Best Current Practices for the Internet Community, and requests discussion and suggestions for improvements.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='101'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='4071'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC4071'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.4371.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC4371' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc4371'>
<front>
<title>BCP 101 Update for IPR Trust</title>
<author initials='B.' surname='Carpenter' fullname='B. Carpenter' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='L.' surname='Lynch' fullname='L. Lynch' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<date year='2006' month='January' />
<abstract><t>This document updates BCP 101 to take account of the new IETF Intellectual Property Trust.  This document specifies an Internet Best Current Practices for the Internet Community, and requests discussion and suggestions for improvements.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='101'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='4371'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC4371'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.7691.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC7691' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc7691'>
<front>
<title>Updating the Term Dates of IETF Administrative Oversight Committee (IAOC) Members</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Bradner' fullname='S. Bradner' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<date year='2015' month='November' />
<abstract><t>BCP 101 defines the start and end dates for the terms of IETF Administrative Oversight Committee (IAOC) members; these terms have proven to be impractical.  This memo updates BCP 101 to direct the IAOC to establish more practical start and end dates for terms of IAOC members.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='101'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='7691'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC7691'/>
</reference>
</referencegroup>
