<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<referencegroup anchor="BCP222" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/bcp222">
<!-- reference.RFC.8552.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC8552' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8552'>
<front>
<title>Scoped Interpretation of DNS Resource Records through &quot;Underscored&quot; Naming of Attribute Leaves</title>
<author initials='D.' surname='Crocker' fullname='D. Crocker'><organization /></author>
<date year='2019' month='March' />
<abstract><t>Formally, any DNS Resource Record (RR) may occur under any domain name.  However, some services use an operational convention for defining specific interpretations of an RRset by locating the records in a DNS branch under the parent domain to which the RRset actually applies.  The top of this subordinate branch is defined by a naming convention that uses a reserved node name, which begins with the underscore character (e.g., &quot;_name&quot;).  The underscored naming construct defines a semantic scope for DNS record types that are associated with the parent domain above the underscored branch.  This specification explores the nature of this DNS usage and defines the &quot;Underscored and Globally Scoped DNS Node Names&quot; registry with IANA. The purpose of this registry is to avoid collisions resulting from the use of the same underscored name for different services.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='222'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='8552'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC8552'/>
</reference>
<!-- reference.RFC.8553.xml -->
<reference  anchor='RFC8553' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8553'>
<front>
<title>DNS Attrleaf Changes: Fixing Specifications That Use Underscored Node Names</title>
<author initials='D.' surname='Crocker' fullname='D. Crocker'><organization /></author>
<date year='2019' month='March' />
<abstract><t>Using an underscore for a prefix creates a space for constrained interoperation of resource records.  Original uses of an underscore character as a domain node name prefix were specified without the benefit of an IANA registry.  This produced an entirely uncoordinated set of name-creation activities, all drawing from the same namespace. A registry for these names has now been defined by RFC 8552. However, the existing specifications that use underscored naming need to be modified in order to be in line with the new registry.  This document specifies those changes.  The changes preserve existing software and operational practice, while adapting the specifications for those practices to the newer underscore registry model.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='222'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='8553'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC8553'/>
</reference>
</referencegroup>
