<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.dulinski-alto-inter-problem-statement'>
<front>
<title>Inter-ALTO Communication Problem Statement</title>

<author initials='Z' surname='Dulinski' fullname='Zbigniew Dulinski'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='P' surname='Wydrych' fullname='Piotr Wydrych'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Stankiewicz' fullname='Rafal Stankiewicz'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='11' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>This draft considers an approach to the optimization of the traffic generated by the overlay (peer-to-peer) applications, where some information on inter-AS (Autonomous System) paths is obtained with the usage of dedicated communication scheme known as inter-ALTO communication.  The large amount of network traffic generated by overlay applications requires effective management.  This traffic traverses inter-AS links and thus generates substantial costs for the operators and poses problems with overload on the external and internal links.  The traffic is not time-stable as the peers connect and disconnect very often.  Additionally, when the overlay traffic is observed on inter-AS links, it can be seen that sources and destinations change in a very short period of time.  The ALTO (Application-Layer Traffic Optimization) service provides the information that enables more efficient management of the overlay traffic.  Such applications can use the information to perform better-than-random peer selection. The ALTO servers are responsible for a pre-selection procedure; the final selection is done by overlay clients and then the ALTO protocol conveys network information to applications.  To be credible, this information should be as close to real network situation as possible. However, some types of data are not hold by an operator, but they should be gained on the basis of the additional information exchange with other AS operators.  This document presents rationale for the need of introduction of the inter-ALTO communication.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-dulinski-alto-inter-problem-statement-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-dulinski-alto-inter-problem-statement-01.txt' />
</reference>
