<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.hixie-thewebsocketprotocol'>
<front>
<title>The Web Socket protocol</title>

<author initials='I' surname='Hickson' fullname='Ian Hickson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='December' day='6' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>The Web Socket protocol enables two-way communication between a user agent running untrusted code running in a controlled environment to a remote host that has opted-in to communications from that code.  The security model used for this is the Origin-based security model commonly used by Web browsers.  The protocol consists of an initial handshake followed by basic message framing, layered over TCP.  The goal of this technology is to provide a mechanism for browser-based applications that need two-way communication with servers that does not rely on opening multiple HTTP connections (e.g. using XMLHttpRequest or &lt;iframe>s and long polling).Author's note  This document is automatically generated from the same source document as the HTML5 specification.  [HTML5]  Please send feedback to either the hybi@ietf.org list or the whatwg@whatwg.org list.  Status of this Memo  This Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with the provisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.  Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups.  Note that other groups may also distribute working documents as Internet- Drafts.  Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six months and may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at any time.  It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as reference material or to cite them other than as "work in progress."  The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed at http://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.  The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed at http://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.  This Internet-Draft will expire on June 10, 2010.  Copyright Notice  Copyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as the document authors.  All rights reserved.  This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's Legal Provisions Relating to IETF Documents (http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date of publication of this document.  Please review these documents carefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respect to this document.  Code Components extracted from this document must include Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e of the Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty as described in the BSD License.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-hixie-thewebsocketprotocol-62' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-hixie-thewebsocketprotocol-62.txt' />
</reference>
