<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.cui-softwire-pet'>
<front>
<title>IPv4/IPv6 Coexistence Framework (PET)</title>

<author initials='Y' surname='Cui' fullname='Yong Cui'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Xu' fullname='Mingwei Xu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Wang' fullname='Shengling Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Wu' fullname='Jianping Wu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='X' surname='Li' fullname='Xing Li'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Metz' fullname='Chris Metz'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='26' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>IPv4 and IPv6 are expected to coexist for a long period.  Currently, there are many IPv4/IPv6 transition/coexistence technologies, which can be generally divided into two categories: translation and tunneling.  Both translation and tunneling have limitations and application scopes.  In some typical transition scenarios, tunneling and translation are needed at the same time.  In addition, there may be multiple network devices capable of doing translation or tunneling along the end-to-end path.  It's important to choose particular device(devices) for doing translation or tunneling.  This draft presents an IPv4-IPv6 transition/coexistence framework named PET (short for Prefixing, Encapsulation and Translation).  PET is a network side solution which includes fundamental elements needed in various transition scenarios.  In PET framework, signaling is required for transition devices to exchange necessary information and negotiate how to do combine transition and tunneling cooperatively. This draft also addresses how to deploy PETs and analyze the advantages and disadvantages of typical transition technologies that PET may adopt.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-cui-softwire-pet-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-cui-softwire-pet-01.txt' />
</reference>
