<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.funk-tls-inner-application-extension'>
<front>
<title>TLS Inner Application Extension (TLS/IA)</title>

<author initials='P' surname='Funk' fullname='Paul Funk'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='7' year='2006' />

<abstract><t>This document defines a new TLS extension called "Inner Application". When TLS is used with the Inner Application extension (TLS/IA), additional messages are exchanged after completion of the TLS handshake, in effect providing an extended handshake prior to the start of upper layer data communications. Each TLS/IA message contains an encrypted sequence of Attribute-Value-Pairs (AVPs) from the RADIUS/Diameter namespace. Hence, the AVPs defined in RADIUS and Diameter have the same meaning in TLS/AI; that is, each attribute code point refers to the same logical attribute in any of these protocols. Arbitrary "applications" may be implemented using the AVP exchange. Possible applications include EAP or other forms of user authentication, client integrity checking, provisioning of additional tunnels, and the like. Use of the RADIUS/Diameter namespace provides natural compatibility between TLS/IA applications and widely deployed AAA infrastructures. It is anticipated that TLS/IA will be used with and without subsequent protected data communication within the tunnel established by the handshake. For example, TLS/IA may be used to secure an HTTP data connection, allowing more robust password-based user authentication to occur than would otherwise be possible using mechanisms available in HTTP. TLS/IA may also be used for its handshake portion alone; for example, EAP-TTLSv1 encapsulates a TLS/IA handshake in EAP as a means to mutually authenticate a client and server and establish keys for a separate data connection.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-funk-tls-inner-application-extension-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-funk-tls-inner-application-extension-02.txt' />
</reference>
