<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.natarajan-tsvwg-sctp-nrsack'>
<front>
<title>Non-Renegable Selective Acknowledgements (NR-SACKs) for SCTP</title>

<author initials='P' surname='Natarajan' fullname='Preethi  Natarajan'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='P' surname='Amer' fullname='Paul Amer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Yilmaz' fullname='Ertugrul Yilmaz'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Stewart' fullname='Randall Stewart'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Iyengar' fullname='Janardhan Iyengar'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='August' day='27' year='2008' />

<abstract><t>Stream Control Transmission Protocol (SCTP) [RFC4960] specifies Selective Acknowledgements (SACKs) to allow a transport layer data receiver to acknowledge DATA chunks which arrive out-of-order.  In SCTP, SACK information is advisory because the data receiver is permitted to renege; that is, later discard a DATA chunk which previously has been SACKed.  Since delivery of a SACKed out-of-order DATA chunk is not guaranteed, a copy of this DATA chunk MUST be kept in the data sender's retransmission queue until this DATA chunk is cumulatively acked.  This document specifies Non-Renegable Selective Acknowledgements (NR- SACKs), an extension to SCTP's acknowledgment mechanism.  NR-SACKs enable a data receiver to explicitly acknowledge out-of-order DATA chunks that have been delivered to the receiving application. (Recall that, in SCTP, out-of-order data sometimes can be delivered.) NR-SACKs also enable a data receiver to indicate any out-of-order DATA chunks on which the receiver guarantees never to renege.  As opposed to SACKed DATA chunks, a sender can consider NR-SACKed DATA chunks as never requiring retransmission, thus freeing space in the data sender's retransmission queue sooner.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-natarajan-tsvwg-sctp-nrsack-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-natarajan-tsvwg-sctp-nrsack-02.txt' />
</reference>
