<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.wang-opsawg-policies-migration-gap-analysis'>
<front>
<title>Survey and Gap Analysis for Policies and Dynamic Information Migration in Data Center</title>

<author initials='W' surname='Danhua' fullname='Wang Danhua'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Yingjie' fullname='Gu Yingjie'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='June' day='20' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>With the virtualization of Data Center, the number of VM explodes. VM can play different roles in Data Center, such as end-host, server, firewall, and so on.  Also, VM can be migrated to any places within Data Center, even to another Data Center.  Since running services shouldn't be significantly interrupted while VM migrates, VM related policies and dynamic information generated by any devices must be transferred to destination devices during a proper short period. [I.D-gu-opsa-policies-migration-00] has introduced more detail problem statement and corresponding considerations.  We wish we could benefit from existing work to realize accurate dynamic information migration (DIM).  Therefore, we engaged in the investigation of related IETF works right after general requirements of DIM are defined.  Since the solution for DIM has not been decided yet, and the author can envision several kinds of solution, e.g. centralized or distributed.  It's unrealistic to enumerate all the related works for an uncertain solution.  So, in this draft, only the most related IETF work, MIDCOM protocol, has been evaluated to find out whether it can fully support DIM or which characteristics can be reused in DIM. The author would like analyze other related IETF works when the WG make further decision on DIM solution.  Following a short description of general DIM requirements, this draft presents a brief survey of MIDCOM protocol, and then lists the gap between MIDCOM and DIM requirements.  The final section presents possible working scope on the topic of DIM in IETF.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-wang-opsawg-policies-migration-gap-analysis-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-wang-opsawg-policies-migration-gap-analysis-00.txt' />
</reference>
