<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-ecrit-data-only-ea'>
<front>
<title>Non-Interactive Emergency Calls</title>

<author initials='B' surname='Rosen' fullname='Brian Rosen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Schulzrinne' fullname='Henning Schulzrinne'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Tschofenig' fullname='Hannes Tschofenig'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Gellens' fullname='Randall Gellens'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='30' year='2020' />

<abstract><t>RFC 6443 'Framework for Emergency Calling Using Internet Multimedia' describes how devices use the Internet to place emergency calls and how Public Safety Answering Points (PSAPs) handle Internet multimedia emergency calls natively.  The exchange of multimedia traffic for emergency services involves a Session Initiation Protocol (SIP) session establishment starting with a SIP INVITE that negotiates various parameters for that session.  These calls involve a person, who uses the interactive media to communicate with the PSAP.  In some cases, however, the transmission of application data is all that is needed, and no interactive media channel is established. Examples of such environments include alerts issued by a temperature sensor, burglar alarm, or chemical spill sensor.  Often these alerts are conveyed as one-shot data transmissions.  These type of interactions are called 'non-interactive emergency calls'.  This document describes use of a SIP MESSAGE transaction containing a container for the data based on the Common Alerting Protocol (CAP). MESSAGE does not establish a session, which differentiates this type of emergency request from a SIP INVITE, which would.  Any device that needs to initiate a request for emergency services where no interactive media channel will be established would use the mechanisms in this document.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-ecrit-data-only-ea-20' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-ecrit-data-only-ea-20.txt' />
</reference>
