<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-ccamp-gmpls-mln-reqs'>
<front>
<title>Requirements for GMPLS-Based Multi-Region and Multi-Layer Networks  (MRN/MLN)</title>

<author initials='K' surname='Shiomoto' fullname='Kohei Shiomoto'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Papadimitriou' fullname='Dimitri Papadimitriou'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Roux' fullname='Jean-Louis Roux'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Vigoureux' fullname='Martin Vigoureux'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Brungard' fullname='Deborah Brungard'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Oki' fullname='Eiji Oki'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='I' surname='Inoue' fullname='Ichiro Inoue'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Dotaro' fullname='Emmanuel Dotaro'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='February' day='8' year='2008' />

<abstract><t>Most of the initial efforts to utilize Generalized MPLS (GMPLS) have been related to environments hosting devices with a single switching capability. The complexity raised by the control of such data planes is similar to that seen in classical IP/MPLS networks. By extending MPLS to support multiple switching technologies, GMPLS provides a comprehensive framework for the control of a multi- layered network of either a single switching technology or multiple switching technologies.  In GMPLS, a switching technology domain defines a region, and a network of multiple switching types is referred to in this document as a Multi-Region Network (MRN). When referring in general to a layered network, which may consist of either a single or multiple regions, this document uses the term, Multi-Layer Network (MLN). This document defines a framework for GMPLS based multi-region / multi-layer networks and lists a set of functional requirements.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-ccamp-gmpls-mln-reqs-08' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-ccamp-gmpls-mln-reqs-08.txt' />
</reference>
