<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-mpls-tp-framework'>
<front>
<title>A Framework for MPLS in Transport Networks</title>

<author initials='M' surname='Bocci' fullname='Matthew Bocci'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Bryant' fullname='Stewart Bryant'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Frost' fullname='Dan Frost'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Levrau' fullname='Lieven Levrau'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Berger' fullname='Lou Berger'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='22' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>This document specifies an architectural framework for the application of Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS) to the construction of packet-switched equivalents of traditional circuit- switched carrier networks.  It describes a common set of protocol functions - the MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) - that supports the operational models and capabilities typical of such networks, including signaled or explicitly provisioned bi-directional connection-oriented paths, protection and restoration mechanisms, comprehensive Operations, Administration and Maintenance (OAM) functions, and network operation in the absence of a dynamic control plane or IP forwarding support.  Some of these functions are defined in existing MPLS specifications, while others require extensions to existing specifications to meet the requirements of the MPLS-TP.  This document defines the subset of the MPLS-TP applicable in general and to point-to-point paths.  The remaining subset, applicable specifically to point-to-multipoint paths, are out of scope of this document.  This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunications Union Telecommunications Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and PWE3 architectures to support the capabilities and functionalities of a packet transport network as defined by the ITU-T.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-mpls-tp-framework-08' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-mpls-tp-framework-08.txt' />
</reference>
