<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.birkholz-rats-architecture'>
<front>
<title>Architecture and Reference Terminology for Remote Attestation Procedures</title>

<author initials='H' surname='Birkholz' fullname='Henk Birkholz'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Wiseman' fullname='Monty Wiseman'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Tschofenig' fullname='Hannes Tschofenig'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='N' surname='Smith' fullname='Ned Smith'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='11' year='2019' />

<abstract><t>Remote ATtestation ProcedureS (RATS) architecture facilitates the attestation of device characteristics that, in general, are based on specific trustworthiness qualities intrinsic to a device or service. It includes trusted computing functionality provided by device hardware and software that allows trustworthiness qualities to be asserted and verified as part of, or pre-requisite to, the device's normal operation.  The RATS architecture maps corresponding attestation functions and capabilities to specific RATS Roles.  The goal is to enable an appropriate conveyance of evidence about device trustworthiness via network protocols.  RATS Roles provide the endpoint context for understanding the various interaction semantics of the attestation lifecycle.  The RATS architecture provides the building block concepts, semantics, syntax and framework for interoperable attestation while remaining hardware-agnostic.  This flexibility is intended to address a significant variety of use-cases and scenarios involving interoperable attestation.  Example usages include, but are not limited to: financial transactions, voting machines, critical safety systems, network equipment health, or trustworthy end-user device management.  Existing industry attestation efforts may be helpful toward informing RATS architecture.  Such as: Remote Integrity VERification (RIVER), the creation of Entity Attestation Tokens (EAT), software integrity Measurement And ATtestation (MAAT)</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-birkholz-rats-architecture-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-birkholz-rats-architecture-01.txt' />
</reference>
