<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-ccamp-gmpls-g-694-lambda-labels'>
<front>
<title>Generalized Labels for Lambda-Switching Capable Label Switching Routers</title>

<author initials='T' surname='Otani' fullname='Tomohiro Otani'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Rabbat' fullname='Richard Rabbat'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Shiba' fullname='Sidney Shiba'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Guo' fullname='Hongxiang Guo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Miyazaki' fullname='Keiji Miyazaki'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Caviglia' fullname='Diego Caviglia'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Li' fullname='Dan Li'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Tsuritani' fullname='Takehiro Tsuritani'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='11' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>Technology in the optical domain is constantly evolving and as a consequence new equipment providing lambda switching capability has been developed and is currently being deployed.  Generalized MPLS (GMPLS) is a family of protocols that can be used to operate networks built from a range of technologies including wavelength (or lambda) switching. For this purpose, GMPLS defined that a wavelength label only has significance between two neighbors and global wavelength semantics are not considered.  In order to facilitate interoperability in a network composed of next generation lambda switch-capable equipment, this document defines a standard lambda label format that is compliant with Dense Wavelength Division Multiplexing and Coarse Wavelength Division Multiplexing grids defined by the International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector. The label format defined in this document can be used in GMPLS signaling and routing protocols.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-ccamp-gmpls-g-694-lambda-labels-11' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-ccamp-gmpls-g-694-lambda-labels-11.txt' />
</reference>
