<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ma-netext-pmip-handover'>
<front>
<title>Network-based Inter-domain handover Support for Proxy Mobile IPv6</title>

<author initials='Z' surname='Ma' fullname='Zhengming Ma'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Wang' fullname='Ke Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='F' surname='Zhang' fullname='Fei Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='24' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>[RFC5380] prompts the Inner-domain handover of the MN in Proxy Mobile IPv6(PMIPv6).This document describes network-based Inter-domain handover functionality and corresponding mobility options for PMIPv6.This document strictly abides by the two principle describes in PMIPv6:  (a)The movement of MN is transparent to CN.  (b)MN doesn't participate in any mobility-related signaling.LMA and MAG are responsible for managing IP mobility on behalf of the host.  The points of this document are as follows:  (1) Concepts: The MN's Home Agent(HA) ,Home Address (HoA) and Care-of address(CoA) is not only for user but also for the specific session.MN initiating a session uses the address assigned by the LMA which the MN is registered at the moment as the HoA for the session.The user initiating a session uses the address assigned by the LMA which the MN moves to as the CoA for the session.  (2) Binding Cache:Every local mobility anchor must maintain two Binding Cache entries for each currently registered mobile node.  One is Inner-domain BCE,the other is Inter-domain BCE.  Inner-domain BCE maintains the binding between MN's Proxy-CoA and MN's HoA.  Inter- domain BCE maintains the bingding between CN's HoA and CN's CoA.  (3)Communication:For the user initiating a session or accepting a session,no matter how it moves,the HoA for the session is unchanged,the source address of the data packets is the user's own HoA,and the destination address of the the data packets is the HoA of CN.All the reverse tunneled packets that the local mobility anchor received from the mobile access gateway, after removing the tunnel header MUST be routed to the destination specified in the inner packet header.  According to looking up the Inter-domain BCE,LMA gets the CoA of CN.  Then ,LMA encapsulates the packets to route to CN.On receiving a packet from a correspondent node with the destination address matching a mobile node's home network prefix(es), the local mobility anchor MUST first remove the outer header before forwarding the packet.  Then,LMA looks up the Inner-domain BCE to forward the packets to the right MAG.  (4)Updates:When MN moves to visited LMA(MN-vLMA),MN-vLMA will do three things.  Firstly MN-vLMA will assign a MN-CoA for MN and build up the Inner- domain BCE for MN.  Secondly,MN-vLMA will sends message to MN-hLMA to get the HoA of CN .Then,MN-vLMA builds up the binding between CN-HoA and CN-HoA in the Inter-domain BCE.Thirdly, MN-vLMA sends message to CN-LMA wiht the MN-CoA and MN-HoA included in the message to help CN- LMA updating the Inter-domain BCE for MN.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ma-netext-pmip-handover-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ma-netext-pmip-handover-00.txt' />
</reference>
