<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-roll-urban-routing-reqs'>
<front>
<title>Urban WSNs Routing Requirements in Low Power and Lossy Networks</title>

<author initials='M' surname='Dohler' fullname='Mischa  Dohler'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Watteyne' fullname='Thomas Watteyne'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Winter' fullname='Tim Winter'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Barthel' fullname='Dominique Barthel'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Jacquenet' fullname='Christian Jacquenet'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Madhusudan' fullname='Giyyarpuram Madhusudan'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Chegaray' fullname='Gabriel Chegaray'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='21' year='2008' />

<abstract><t>The application-specific routing requirements for Urban Low Power and Lossy Networks (U-LLNs) are presented in this document.  In the near future, sensing and actuating nodes will be placed outdoors in urban environments so as to improve the people's living conditions as well as to monitor compliance with increasingly strict environmental laws. These field nodes are expected to measure and report a wide gamut of data, such as required in smart metering, waste disposal, meteorological, pollution and allergy reporting applications.  The majority of these nodes is expected to communicate wirelessly which - given the limited radio range and the large number of nodes - requires the use of suitable routing protocols.  The design of such protocols will be mainly impacted by the limited resources of the nodes (memory, processing power, battery, etc.) and the particularities of the outdoor urban application scenarios.  As such, for a wireless Routing Over Low power and Lossy networks (ROLL) solution to be useful, the protocol(s) ought to be energy-efficient, scalable, and autonomous.  This documents aims to specify a set of requirements reflecting these and further U-LLNs tailored characteristics.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-roll-urban-routing-reqs-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-roll-urban-routing-reqs-02.txt' />
</reference>
