<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-netconf-zerotouch'>
<front>
<title>Zero Touch Provisioning for NETCONF or RESTCONF based Management</title>

<author initials='K' surname='Watsen' fullname='Kent Watsen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Abrahamsson' fullname='Mikael Abrahamsson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='I' surname='Farrer' fullname='Ian Farrer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='September' day='11' year='2017' />

<abstract><t>This draft presents a secure technique for establishing a NETCONF or RESTCONF connection between a newly deployed device, configured with just its preconfigured initial state (e.g., factory default settings), and its deployment specific network management system (NMS).  Editorial Note (To be removed by RFC Editor)  This draft contains many placeholder values that need to be replaced with finalized values at the time of publication.  This note summarizes all of the substitutions that are needed.  Please note that no other RFC Editor instructions are specified anywhere else in this document.  Artwork in the IANA Considerations section contains placeholder values for DHCP options pending IANA assignment.  Please apply the following replacements:  o  "OPTION_V4_ZEROTOUCH_REDIRECT" --> the option code assigned for the "DHCPv4 Zero Touch Option" option  o  "OPTION_V6_ZEROTOUCH_REDIRECT" --> the option code assigned for the "DHCPv6 Zero Touch Option" option  Artwork in this document contains shorthand references to drafts in progress.  Please apply the following replacements:  o  "XXXX" --> the assigned RFC value for this draft  Artwork in this document contains placeholder values for the date of publication of this draft.  Please apply the following replacement:  o  "2017-09-11" --> the publication date of this draft Please update the following references to reflect their final RFC assignments:  o  I-D.ieft-netconf-netconf-client-server  The following one Appendix section is to be removed prior to publication:  o  Appendix A.  Change Log</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-netconf-zerotouch-17' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-netconf-zerotouch-17.txt' />
</reference>
