<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-paws-problem-stmt-usecases-rqmts'>
<front>
<title>Protocol to Access White Space (PAWS) Database: Use Cases and Requirements</title>

<author initials='A' surname='Mancuso' fullname='Anthony Mancuso'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Patil' fullname='Basavaraj Patil'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='29' year='2013' />

<abstract><t>Portions of the radio spectrum that are assigned to a particular use but are unused or unoccupied at specific locations and times are defined as "white space."  The concept of allowing additional transmissions (which may or may not be licensed) in white space is a technique to "unlock" existing spectrum for new use.  An obvious requirement is that these additional transmissions do not interfere with the assigned use of the spectrum.  One approach to using white space spectrum at a given time and location is to verify spectrum availability with a database that manages spectrum sharing and provides spectrum-availability information.  The IETF has undertaken to develop a Protocol to Access Spectrum Database [1] for such a management database.  This document describes a number of possible use cases of white space spectrum and technology as well as a set of requirements for the database query protocol.  The concept of white spaces is described along with the problems that need to be addressed to enable white space spectrum for additional uses without causing interference to currently assigned use.  Use of white space is enabled by querying a database that stores information about spectrum availability at any given location and time.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-paws-problem-stmt-usecases-rqmts-12' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-paws-problem-stmt-usecases-rqmts-12.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-paws-problem-stmt-usecases-rqmts-12.pdf' />
</reference>
