<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.hares-ibnemo-overview'>
<front>
<title>Intent-Based Nemo Problem statement</title>

<author initials='S' surname='Hares' fullname='Susan Hares'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='6' year='2015' />

<abstract><t>As IP networks grow more complicated, these networks require a new interaction mechanism between customers and their networks based on intent rather than detailed specifics.  An intent-based protocol language is need to enable customers to easily describe their diverse intent for network connectivity to the network management systems. This document describes the problem Intent-Based NEtwork Modeling (IB-Nemo) language is trying to solve, a summary of the use cases that demonstrate this problem, and a proposed scope of work.  Part of the scope is the validation of the language as a minimal subset.  The IB-NEMO language is a protocol language for interactions between an application and a network manager/controller.  Some would call this boundary between the application and the network management system as northbound interface (NBI), and any protocol language that crosses this as an NBI.  IB-Nemo focuses on creating minimal subset of the total possible Intent-Based desired commands.  By creating a minimal subset (about 20% of the total possible), the IB-Nemo language can be a simple Intent interface for most applications (hopefully 80%).  Part of validation of this language is to to determine what data models should result in the network controller from different use cases.  This way as IB-Nemo protocol language is reduced the effort can verify that the critical information is stilled passed.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-hares-ibnemo-overview-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-hares-ibnemo-overview-00.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-hares-ibnemo-overview-00.pdf' />
</reference>
