<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-mpls-tp-temporal-hitless-psm'>
<front>
<title>Enhanced path segment monitoring</title>

<author initials='A' surname='D&apos;Alessandro' fullname='Alessandro D&apos;Alessandro'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Andersson' fullname='Loa Andersson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Paul' fullname='Manuel Paul'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Ueno' fullname='Satoshi Ueno'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Arai' fullname='Kaoru Arai'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Koike' fullname='Yoshinori Koike'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='December' day='18' year='2015' />

<abstract><t>The MPLS transport profile (MPLS-TP) has been standardized to enable carrier-grade packet transport and to complement converged packet network deployments.  The most attractive features of MPLS-TP are the OAM functions.  These functions enable maintenance tools that may be exploited by network operators and service providers for fault location, survivability, performance monitoring, in-service and out- of-service measurements.  One of the most important mechanisms that is common for transport network operation is fault localisation.  A segment monitoring function of a transport path is effective in terms of extension of the maintenance work and indispensable, particularly when the OAM function is activated only between end points.  However, the current approach defined for MPLS-TP of segment monitoring has some drawbacks.  This document elaborates on the problem statement for the Sub-path Maintenance Elements (SPMEs) which provide monitoring of a segment of a set of transport paths (LSPs or MS-PWs).  Based on the identified problems, this document provides considerations for the specification of new requirements to consider a new improved mechanism for hitless transport path segment monitoring to be named Enhanced Path Segment Monitoring (EPSM).</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-mpls-tp-temporal-hitless-psm-09' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-mpls-tp-temporal-hitless-psm-09.txt' />
</reference>
