<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.thompson-cdni-atis-scenarios'>
<front>
<title>ATIS Internet Sourced Content Initiative and Relevance to CDNI</title>

<author initials='B' surname='Thompson' fullname='Bruce Thompson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Kobayashi' fullname='Akira Kobayashi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='29' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>The ATIS IPTV Interoperability Forum (IIF) is a leading developer of requirements, standards, and specifications for Internet Protocol Television, or IPTV.  IIF has specified an architecture for Content On Demand applications which was published as the [ATIS-0800042] IPTV Content on Demand (CoD) Service specification.  ATIS IIF is now working on revision 2 of this document.  Revision 2 of ATIS CoD specification includes an additional work item called "Internet Sourced Content" which includes "off net delivery".  Both Internet Sourced Content and off net delivery will address scenarios that include delivery of content from a Content Service Provider through multiple CDNs operated by different organizations to a user agent. This document provides information on [ATIS-0800042], and the Internet Sourced Content and off net Delivery use cases that are relevant to CDNI.  The ATIS IIF architecture group focuses on developing architectures and prefers to reference existing protocols where ever possible.  If, and as, the IETF CDNI effort progresses, the ATIS IIF architecture group will be evaluating the protocols defined by the CDNI working group for inclusion in the CDN interconnect scenarios defined as part of the Internet Sourced Content and off net Delivery use cases.  A goal of the present document is to illustrate the Internet Sourced Content and off net Delivery use cases defined in revision 2 of the ATIS CoD architecture that are relevant to the IETF CDNI work.  It is hoped that these use cases can also be used to guide requirements for the development of IETF CDNI protocols.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-thompson-cdni-atis-scenarios-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-thompson-cdni-atis-scenarios-00.txt' />
</reference>
