<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.mwdt-ccamp-fmwk'>
<front>
<title>A framework for Management and Control of microwave and millimeter wave interface parameters</title>

<author initials='J' surname='Ahlberg' fullname='Jonas Ahlberg'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Contreras' fullname='Luis Contreras'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Ye' fullname='Min Ye'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Vaupotic' fullname='Marko Vaupotic'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Tantsura' fullname='Jeff Tantsura'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Kawada' fullname='Koji Kawada'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='X' surname='Li' fullname='Xi Li'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='I' surname='Akiyoshi' fullname='Ippei Akiyoshi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Bernardos' fullname='Carlos Bernardos'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='28' year='2016' />

<abstract><t>To ensure an efficient data transport, meeting the requirements requested by today's transport services, the unification of control and management of microwave and millimeter wave radio link interfaces is a precondition for seamless multilayer networking and automated network wide provisioning and operation.  This document describes the required characteristics and use cases for control and management of radio link interface parameters using a YANG Data Model. It focuses on the benefits of a standardized management model that is aligned with how other packet technology interfaces in a microwave/millimeter wave node are modeled, the need to support core parameters and at the same time allow for optional product/feature specific parameters supporting new, unique innovative features until they have become mature enough to be included in the standardized model.  The purpose is to create a framework for identification of the necessary information elements and definition of a YANG Data Model for control and management of the radio link interfaces in a microwave/millimeter wave node.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-mwdt-ccamp-fmwk-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-mwdt-ccamp-fmwk-00.txt' />
</reference>
