<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.despotovic-alto-feedback-cp'>
<front>
<title>ALTO-FCP: Application Layer Traffic Optimization Feedback-Based Client Protocol</title>

<author initials='Z' surname='Despotovic' fullname='Zoran Despotovic'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Kellerer' fullname='Wolfgang Kellerer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Spirou' fullname='Spiros Spirou'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Staehle' fullname='Dirk Staehle'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Rodriguez' fullname='Maria Rodriguez'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='I' surname='Papafili' fullname='Ioanna Papafili'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='6' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>In some networked applications, such as peer-to-peer file sharing, the same resource (e.g., a file or a server process) is available at several potential resource providers. Resource consumers typically try to select providers so that application performance is improved, establishing an overlay topology of direct logical links in the process. However, lack of reliable information about the underlying network can lead to poor choices and suboptimal application performance. In addition, resulting application traffic is largely oblivious to technical, economical, and political constraints at the network level, causing problems for network operators.  This document describes a protocol that facilitates the exchange of information between an overlay and the underlying network. Such information can be used at each layer to make decisions that are not detrimental to the other layer or, ideally, are beneficial to both.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-despotovic-alto-feedback-cp-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-despotovic-alto-feedback-cp-00.txt' />
</reference>
