<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-alto-path-vector'>
<front>
<title>ALTO Extension: Path Vector</title>

<author initials='K' surname='Gao' fullname='Kai Gao'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Lee' fullname='Young Lee'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Randriamasy' fullname='Sabine Randriamasy'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Yang' fullname='Y. Yang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Zhang' fullname='J. Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='November' day='3' year='2019' />

<abstract><t>This document defines an ALTO extension that allows an ALTO information resource to provide not only preferences but also correlations of the paths between different PIDs or endpoints.  The extended information, including aggregations of network components on the paths and their properties, can be used to improve the robustness and performance for applications in some new usage scenarios, such as high-speed data transfers and traffic optimization using in-network storage and computation.  This document reuses the mechanisms of the ALTO base protocol and the Unified Property extension, such as Information Resource Directory (IRD) capabilities and entity domains, to negotiate and exchange path correlation information.  Meanwhile, it uses an extended compound message to fully represent the path correlation information, for better server scalability and message modularity.  Specifically, the extension 1) introduces abstract network element (ANE) as an abstraction for an aggregation of network components and encodes a network path as a "path vector", i.e., an array of ANEs traversed from the source to the destination, 2) encodes properties of abstract network elements in a unified property map, and 3) encapsulates the two types of information in a multipart message.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-alto-path-vector-09' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-alto-path-vector-09.txt' />
</reference>
