<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-opsawg-mpls-tp-oam-def'>
<front>
<title>"The OAM Acronym Soup"</title>

<author initials='L' surname='Andersson' fullname='Loa Andersson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Helvoort' fullname='Huub Helvoort'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Bonica' fullname='Ronald Bonica'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Romascanu' fullname='Dan Romascanu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Mansfield' fullname='Scott Mansfield'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='February' day='11' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>At first glance the acronym "OAM" seems to be well known and well understood.  Looking at it a bit more closely reveals a set of recurring problems that are revisited time and again.  This document has one primary and one secondary goal.  The primary goal is to find an understanding of OAM that is useful for the MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) effort.  The secondary goal is to make this understanding applicable in a wider scope.  This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and PWE3 architectures to support the capabilities and functionalities of a packet transport network.  This Informational Internet-Draft is aimed at achieving IETF Consensus before publication as an RFC and will be subject to an IETF Last Call.  [RFC Editor, please remove this note before publication as an RFC and insert the correct Streams Boilerplate to indicate that the published RFC has IETF Consensus.]</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-opsawg-mpls-tp-oam-def-03' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-opsawg-mpls-tp-oam-def-03.txt' />
</reference>
