<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.livingood-dnsop-negative-trust-anchors'>
<front>
<title>Definition and Use of DNSSEC Negative Trust Anchors</title>

<author initials='P' surname='Ebersman' fullname='Paul Ebersman'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Griffiths' fullname='Chris Griffiths'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Kumari' fullname='Warren Kumari'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Livingood' fullname='Jason Livingood'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Weber' fullname='Ralf Weber'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='September' day='25' year='2014' />

<abstract><t>DNS Security Extensions (DNSSEC) is now entering widespread deployment.  However, domain signing tools and processes are not yet as mature and reliable as is the case for non-DNSSEC-related domain administration tools and processes.  One potential technique to mitigate this is to use a Negative Trust Anchor, which is defined in this document.  This document discusses Trust Anchors for DNSSEC and defines a Negative Trust Anchor, which is potentially useful during the transition to ubiquitous DNSSEC deployment.  These are configured locally on a particular instance of a validating DNS recursive resolver and can shield end users of such a resolver from the DNSSEC- related authoritative name server operational errors that appear to be somewhat typical during the transition to ubiquitous DNSSEC deployment.  Negative Trust Anchors are intended to be temporary, and should not be distributed by IANA or any other organization outside of the administrative boundary of the organization locally implementing a Negative Trust Anchor.  Finally, Negative Trust Anchors pertain only to DNSSEC and not to Public Key Infrastructures (PKI) such ad X.509.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-livingood-dnsop-negative-trust-anchors-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-livingood-dnsop-negative-trust-anchors-00.txt' />
</reference>
