<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.iulian-advanced-groupware-access-protocol'>
<front>
<title>Advanced Groupware Access Protocol</title>

<author initials='I' surname='Radu' fullname='Iulian Radu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='April' day='20' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>The Advanced Groupware Access Protocol, (AGAP) allows a client to access and store electronic mail messages, contacts, events, files, and configurations on a server.  The electronic mail messages can be grouped in folders.  AGAP also provides the capability for an offline client to resynchronize with the server.  AGAP does not specify a means of posting electronic mail messages; this function is handled by a mail transfer protocol such as SMTP [RFC2821].  It also does not specify a means for exchanging messages with contacts that are reported as being online; this function is handled by an instant messaging protocol such as XMPP [RFC3921].  AGAP includes the following operations for electronic mail messages: creating, deleting, renaming, moving and coping mail folders; checking for new messages; permanently removing messages; moving and coping messages between folders; fetching information about a message; setting and clearing tags for messages; searching in messages; retrieving only a part of a message; marking messages as spam; deleting attachments from a message.  AGAP includes the following operations to manipulate the contacts: creating, deleting, moving, coping, tagging, and searching contacts; checking if a contact is online; fetching information about a contact.  AGAP includes the following operations related to the use of the events: creating, deleting, moving, coping and tagging events in calendar; fetching events details; searching for events.  All entries are read and written in format XML encoded UTF-8 [RFC3629] and each entry is identified by a unique alphanumeric identifier.  AGAP is designed to support access only to a single server per connection.  It is also designed to balance the volume of text exchanged between the server and clients and its readability by humans for debugging.Status of this Memo  This Internet-Draft is submitted in full conformance with the provisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.  Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF).  Note that other groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.  The list of current Internet- Drafts is at http://datatracker.ietf.org/drafts/current/.  Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six months and may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at any time.  It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as reference material or to cite them other than as "work in progress."  This Internet-Draft will expire on October 22, 2010.  Copyright Notice  Copyright (c) 2010 IETF Trust and the persons identified as the document authors.  All rights reserved.  This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's Legal Provisions Relating to IETF Documents (http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date of publication of this document.  Please review these documents carefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respect to this document.  Code Components extracted from this document must include Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e of the Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty as described in the Simplified BSD License.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-iulian-advanced-groupware-access-protocol-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-iulian-advanced-groupware-access-protocol-00.txt' />
</reference>
