<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-avt-rfc2833bis'>
<front>
<title>RTP Payload for DTMF Digits, Telephony Tones and Telephony Signals</title>

<author initials='H' surname='Schulzrinne' fullname='Henning  Schulzrinne'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Taylor' fullname='Tom Taylor'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='June' day='16' year='2006' />

<abstract><t>This memo describes how to carry dual-tone multifrequency (DTMF) signaling, other tone signals and telephony events in RTP packets. It obsoletes RFC 2833. This memo captures and expands upon the basic framework defined in RFC 2833, but retains only the most basic event codes. It sets up an IANA registry to which other event code assignments may be added. Companion documents add event codes to this registry relating to modem, fax, text telephony, and channel-associated signalling events. The remainder of the event codes defined in RFC 2833 are conditionally reserved in case other documents revive their use. See Section 7 and Appendix A for details. [RFC Editor: please change the Informative reference following RFC 4103 to the RFC number assigned to draft-ietf-avt-rfc2833bisdata-08.txt, one of the "companion documents" referred to above.] In terms of procedure, this document provides a number of clarifications to the original document. However, it specifically differs from RFC 2833 by removing the requirement that all compliant implementations support the DTMF events. Instead, compliant implementations taking part in out-of-band negotiations of media stream content indicate what events they support. As well, this memo adds three new procedures to the RFC 2833 framework: subdivision of long events into segments, reporting of multiple events in a single packet, and the concept and reporting of state events.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-avt-rfc2833bis-15' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-avt-rfc2833bis-15.txt' />
</reference>
