<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.corujo-icn-mgmt'>
<front>
<title>ICN Management Considerations</title>

<author initials='D' surname='Corujo' fullname='Daniel Corujo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Pentikousis' fullname='Kostas Pentikousis'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='I' surname='Vidal' fullname='Ivan Vidal'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Garcia-Reinoso' fullname='Jaime Garcia-Reinoso'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Lederer' fullname='Stefan Lederer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Spirou' fullname='Spiros Spirou'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='c' surname='cedric.westphal@huawei.com' fullname='cedric.westphal@huawei.com'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='1' year='2014' />

<abstract><t>ICN has been proposing and evaluating novel ways for reaching on-line content in upcoming Future Internet environments, leveraging intrinsic capabilities such as naming, caching and built-in security. In order to fully realize the capabilities and vision provided by ICN, supportive management procedures need to be ensured, providing the architectures, and the elements that figure in them, with the means to facilitate the delivery of content and the operation of the network.  In the current Internet, these management aspects have been being developed and enhanced in parallel to the existing data protocol and mechanisms, resulting in a plethora of different and hard-to-integrate approaches, but still fulfil indispensable roles and actions for the operation and well-being of the network.  We consider that the availability of management mechanisms for ICN will foster deployment and, as such, should be tackled still in the design and experimentation phases.  In this way, this document addresses and identifies ICN management considerations, under two different settings: a) achieving management operations using ICN-based mechanisms and, b) how to manage ICN procedures themselves.  The ultimate goal is to provide the necessary breadth to establish management mechanisms deployment guidelines in a common way throughout the existing ICN ecosystem of architectures.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-corujo-icn-mgmt-05' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-corujo-icn-mgmt-05.txt' />
</reference>
