<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-urnbis-rfc3406bis-urn-ns-reg'>
<front>
<title>Uniform Resource Name (URN) Namespace Definition Mechanisms</title>

<author initials='A' surname='Hoenes' fullname='Alfred Hoenes'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='December' day='16' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>Uniform Resource Names (URNs) are intended to serve as persistent, location-independent, resource identifiers.  To structure and organize their usage, the URN syntax specifies a hierarchy that horizontally divides the set of possible URNs into "URN Namespaces" that can be individually defined and managed.  URN Namespaces in particular serve to map existing identifier systems into the URN system and thereby make available generic, network-based resolution services for the identified documents, artifacts, and other objects (and their metadata).  To actually leverage such synergetic advantage, URN namespaces need to be specified in a comparable manner, and their Namespace Identifiers (NIDs) need to be registered with IANA, so that naming conflicts are avoided and implementers of services can follow a structured approach in support of various namespaces, guided by the registry to the related documents and the particularities of specific namespaces, as described in these namespace registration documents.  This document serves as a guidleline for authors of URN Namespace definition and registration documents.  It describes the essential content of such documents and how they shall be structured to allow readers familar with the scheme to quickly assess the properties of a specific URN Namespace.  Further, this RFC describes the process to be followed to get a URN Namespace registered with IANA.  This document is a companion document to the revised URN Syntax specification, RFC 2141bis; it supersedes and replaces RFC 3406.  Discussion  This draft version has been obtained by importing the text from RFC 3406 into modern tools and making a first round of updating steps. It is an initial chartered work item of the URNBIS WG.  Discussion of this memo utilizes the urn@ietf.org mailing list.Status of This Memo  This Internet-Draft is submitted in full conformance with the provisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.  Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF).  Note that other groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.  The list of current Internet- Drafts is at http://datatracker.ietf.org/drafts/current/.  Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six months and may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at any time.  It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as reference material or to cite them other than as "work in progress."  This Internet-Draft will expire on June 20, 2011.  Copyright Notice  Copyright (c) 2010 IETF Trust and the persons identified as the document authors.  All rights reserved.  This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's Legal Provisions Relating to IETF Documents (http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date of publication of this document.  Please review these documents carefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respect to this document.  Code Components extracted from this document must include Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e of the Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty as described in the Simplified BSD License.  This document may contain material from IETF Documents or IETF Contributions published or made publicly available before November 10, 2008.  The person(s) controlling the copyright in some of this material may not have granted the IETF Trust the right to allow modifications of such material outside the IETF Standards Process. Without obtaining an adequate license from the person(s) controlling the copyright in such materials, this document may not be modified outside the IETF Standards Process, and derivative works of it may not be created outside the IETF Standards Process, except to format it for publication as an RFC or to translate it into languages other than English.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-urnbis-rfc3406bis-urn-ns-reg-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-urnbis-rfc3406bis-urn-ns-reg-00.txt' />
</reference>
