<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.huang-behave-rfc2767bis'>
<front>
<title>Dual Stack Hosts using the "Bump-In-the-Stack" Technique (BIS)</title>

<author initials='B' surname='Huang' fullname='Bill Huang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Deng' fullname='Hui Deng'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Savolainen' fullname='Teemu Savolainen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='February' day='18' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>This document describes the "Bump-In-the-Stack" (BIS) host based protocol translation mechanism that allows applications supporting only one IP address family to communicate with peers that are reachable or supporting only the other address family.  Furthermore, this technology avoids need for unnecessary double protocol translation in the case where destination is dual-stack enabled.  This specification addresses scenarios where a host is provided dual stack, IPv6 only or IPv4 only network connectivity.  In the dual stack network case, single address family applications in the host will communicate directly with other hosts reachable with the different address family.  In the case of IPv6 only network or IPv6 only destination, IPv4-originated communications have to be be translated into IPv6.  IPv6 communications may have to translated similarly to IPv4.  In the scenario of single address family access network, but dual-stack destination, network based translation is always avoided.  Technically, the BIS-enabled host resolves both IPv4 and IPv6 addresses of the destination and behaves according to received responses.  Acknowledgement of previous work  This document is an update to and directly derivative from Kazuaki TSUCHIYA, Hidemitsu HIGUCHI, and Yoshifumi ATARASHI's [RFC2767], which similarly provides a dual stack host means to communicate with other IPv6 host using existing IPv4 appliations.The original document was a product of the NGTRANS working group.  The changes in this document reflect three components  1.  Supporting IPv6 only network connections  2.  Supporting IPv4 only network connections  3.  Supporting dual stack network connections with translation</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-huang-behave-rfc2767bis-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-huang-behave-rfc2767bis-01.txt' />
</reference>
