<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.tang-iiot-architecture'>
<front>
<title>IPv6 and 5G based Architecture for IIoT</title>

<author initials='C' surname='Tang' fullname='Chaowei Tang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Haotian' fullname='Wen Haotian'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Shuai' fullname='Ruan Shuai'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Huang' fullname='Baojin Huang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='F' surname='Xinxin' fullname='Feng Xinxin'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='November' day='2' year='2020' />

<abstract><t>As the foundation of the current new round of industrial revolution, the Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT) based on Cyber-Physical Systems (CPS) [smart-factory] has become the focus of research in various countries.  In the entire development stage of IIoT, one of the key issues is the standardization of the IIoT architecture.  With the development of intelligent manufacturing technology, the number of the IIoT devices will increase sharply, and a large amount of data will be generated in the industrial manufacturing process.  However, traditional industrial networks cannot meet the IIoT requirements for high data rates, low latency, massive connections, interconnection and interoperability.  The current IIoT architectures also have various limitations: mobility, security, scalability, and communication reliability.  These limitations hinder the development and implementation of IIoT.  As a network layer protocol, IPv6 can solve the problem of IPv4 address exhaustion.  As a high-speed, low- latency wireless communication technology, 5G has great potential in promoting IIoT.  In order to solve the above problems, this draft proposes an IIoT architecture based on IPv6 and 5G.  It can provide high-speed, low-latency communication services, provide massive connectivity, mobility, scalability, security and other features for industrial device.  And the architecture can provide generalized, refined, and flexible network services for devices outside the factory.  And an information model is defined to standardize the representation of information in IIoT.  Finally, the draft discusses security challenges and recommendations in IIoT.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-tang-iiot-architecture-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-tang-iiot-architecture-00.txt' />
</reference>
