<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.duerst-iri-bis'>
<front>
<title>Internationalized Resource Identifiers (IRIs)</title>

<author initials='M' surname='Duerst' fullname='Martin Duerst'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Suignard' fullname='Michel  Suignard'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Masinter' fullname='Larry Masinter'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='13' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>This document defines a new protocol element, the Internationalized Resource Identifier (IRI), as an extension of the Uniform Resource Identifier (URI).  An IRI is a sequence of characters from the Universal Character Set (Unicode/ISO 10646).  A mapping from IRIs to URIs is defined, which provides a means for IRIs to be used instead of URIs, where appropriate, to identify resources.  To accomodate widespread current practice, additional derivative protocol elements are defined, and current practice for resolving IRI-based hypertext references in HTML are outlined.  The approach of defining new protocol elements, rather than updating or extending the definition of URI, was chosen to allow independent orderly transitions as appropriate: other protocols and languages that use URIs and their processing may explicitly choose to allow IRIs or derivative forms.  Guidelines are provided for the use and deployment of IRIs and related protocol elements when revising protocols, formats, and software components that currently deal only with URIs.  [RFC Editor: Please remove this paragraph before publication.]  This is a draft to update RFC 3987 and move towards IETF Draft Standard. For an issues list/change log and additional information (including mailing list information), please see http://www.w3.org/International/iri-edit.  For discussion and comments on this draft, please use the public-iri@w3.org mailing list.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-duerst-iri-bis-06' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-duerst-iri-bis-06.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-duerst-iri-bis-06.pdf' />
</reference>
