<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.otis-dkim-tpa-label'>
<front>
<title>DKIM Third-Party Authorization Label</title>

<author initials='L' surname='header' fullname='List-ID header'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Otis' fullname='Douglas Otis'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Black' fullname='Daniel Black'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='June' day='21' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>A third party authorization label (TPA-Label) is a DNS-based prefix for DKIM ADSP records that allow domains in the From header to authorize acceptable third-party signatures.  This scheme allows autonomously and unilaterally authorizations for a range of third- party domains using scalable, individual DNS transactions.  The extended scope of DKIM signing practice assertions supplant more difficult to administer transparent authorization schemes. Alternatives for facilitating third-party authorizations currently necessitate coordination between two or more domains to synchronously set up selector/key DNS records, DNS zone delegations, and/or a regular exchange of public/private keys.  Checking TPA-Label Resource Records for signing practices may infrequently occur when a message is not compliant with a restrictive ADSP polices where an Author Domain Signature is either missing or invalid.  When a third-party signature is found, TPA-Label Resource Record transactions offer an efficient means for Author Domains to authorize specific third-party signing domains.  Recipients are afforded a method to determine whether authorization exists in situations where other modes of authorization are impractical.  TPA- Label Resource Records permit Author Domain a means to selectively influence message handling, for messages otherwise lacking valid Author Domain signatures.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-otis-dkim-tpa-label-04' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-otis-dkim-tpa-label-04.txt' />
</reference>
