<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.montenegro-httpbis-speed-mobility'>
<front>
<title>HTTP Speed+Mobility</title>

<author initials='R' surname='Trace' fullname='Rob Trace'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Foresti' fullname='Adalberto Foresti'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Singhal' fullname='Sandeep Singhal'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='O' surname='Mazahir' fullname='Osama Mazahir'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Nielsen' fullname='Henrik Nielsen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Montenegro' fullname='Gabriel Montenegro'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='26' year='2012' />

<abstract><t>The design of HTTP--how every application and service on the web communicates today--can positively impact user experience, operational and environmental costs, and even the battery life of the devices you carry around.  Improving HTTP starts with speed.  Apps--not just browsers--should get faster too.  More and more, apps are how people access web services, in addition to their browser.  Improving HTTP should also make mobile better, particularly to ensure great battery life and low network cost on constrained devices.  People and their apps should stay in control of network access.  Finally, to achieve rapid adoption, HTTP 2.0 needs to retain as much compatibility as possible with the existing Web infrastructure.  Done right, HTTP 2.0 can help people connect their devices and applications to the Internet fast, reliably, and securely over a number of diverse networks, with great battery life and low cost.  This document describes "HTTP Speed+Mobility," a proposal for HTTP 2.0 that emphasizes performance improvements and security while at the same time accounting for the important needs of mobile devices and applications.  The proposal starts from both the Google SPDY protocol and the work the IETF has done around WebSockets.  The proposal is not a final product but rather is intended to form a baseline for working group discussion.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-montenegro-httpbis-speed-mobility-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-montenegro-httpbis-speed-mobility-00.txt' />
</reference>
