<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-teas-p2mp-loose-path-reopt'>
<front>
<title>Extensions to Resource Reservation Protocol For Re-optimization of Loosely Routed Point-to-Multipoint Traffic Engineering LSPs</title>

<author initials='T' surname='Saad' fullname='Tarek Saad'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Gandhi' fullname='Rakesh Gandhi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Z' surname='Ali' fullname='Zafar Ali'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Venator' fullname='Robert Venator'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Kamite' fullname='Yuji Kamite'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='December' day='8' year='2014' />

<abstract><t>For a Traffic Engineered (TE) point-to-multipoint (P2MP) Label Switched Path (LSP), it is preferable in some cases to re-evaluate and re-optimize the entire P2MP-TE LSP by re-signaling all its Source-to-Leaf (S2L) sub-LSP(s).  Existing mechanisms, a mechanism for an ingress Label Switched Router (LSR) to trigger a new path re- evaluation request and a mechanism for a mid-point LSR to notify an availability of a preferred path, operate on an individual or a sub- group of S2L sub-LSP(s) basis only.  This document defines RSVP-TE signaling extensions to allow an ingress node of a P2MP-TE LSP to request the re-evaluation of the entire LSP tree containing one or more S2L sub-LSPs whose paths are loose (or abstract) hop expanded, and for a mid-point LSR to notify to the ingress node that a preferable tree exists for the entire P2MP-TE LSP.  This document also defines markers to indicate beginning and end of a S2L sub-LSP descriptor list when RSVP message needs to be fragmented due to large number of S2L sub-LSPs when performing re-optimization.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-teas-p2mp-loose-path-reopt-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-teas-p2mp-loose-path-reopt-00.txt' />
</reference>
