<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.irtf-dtnrg-prophet'>
<front>
<title>Probabilistic Routing Protocol for Intermittently Connected Networks</title>

<author initials='A' surname='Lindgren' fullname='Anders Lindgren'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Doria' fullname='Avri Doria'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Davies' fullname='Elwyn Davies'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Grasic' fullname='Samo Grasic'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='November' day='20' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>This document is a product of the Delay Tolerant Networking Research Group and has been reviewed by that group.  No objections to its publication as an RFC were raised.  This document defines PRoPHET, a Probabilistic Routing Protocol using History of Encounters and Transitivity.  PRoPHET is a routing protocol for intermittently connected networks, where there is no guarantee that a fully connected path between source and destination exists at any time, rendering traditional routing protocols unable to deliver messages between hosts.  These networks are examples of networks where there is a disparity between the latency requirements of applications and the capabilities of the underlying network (networks often referred to as Delay and Disruption Tolerant).  The document presents an architectural overview followed by the protocol specification.  Status of this Memo  This Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with the provisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.  Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups.  Note that other groups may also distribute working documents as Internet- Drafts.  Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six months and may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at any time.  It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as reference material or to cite them other than as "work in progress."  The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed at http://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.  The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed at http://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.  This Internet-Draft will expire on May 24, 2010.  Copyright Notice  Copyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as the document authors.  All rights reserved.  This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's Legal Provisions Relating to IETF Documents (http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date of publication of this document.  Please review these documents carefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respect to this document.  Code Components extracted from this document must include Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e of the Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty as described in the BSD License.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-irtf-dtnrg-prophet-03' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-irtf-dtnrg-prophet-03.txt' />
</reference>
