<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.malis-ccamp-fast-lsps'>
<front>
<title>Requirements for Very Fast Setup of GMPLS LSPs</title>

<author initials='A' surname='Malis' fullname='Andrew Malis'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Skoog' fullname='Ronald Skoog'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Kobrinski' fullname='Haim Kobrinski'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Clapp' fullname='George Clapp'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='V' surname='Shukla' fullname='Vishnu Shukla'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='23' year='2014' />

<abstract><t>The Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) Core Optical Networks (CORONET) program has laid out a vision for the next evolution of IP and optical commercial and government networks, with a focus on highly dynamic and resilient multi-terabit core networks. It anticipates the need for rapid (sub-second) setup and SONET/SDH- like restoration times for high-churn (up to tens of requests per second network-wide and one second to one minute holding times) on- demand wavelength, sub-wavelength and packet services for a variety of applications (e.g., grid computing, cloud computing, data visualization, fast data transfer, etc.).  This must be done while meeting stringent call blocking requirements, and while minimizing the use of resources such as time slots, switch ports, wavelength conversion and wavelength-km.  This document discusses the requirements for extensions to Generalized Multi-Protocol Label Switching (GMPLS) signaling for expediting the control of Label Switched Paths (LSPs), including sub- wavelengths (e.g., OTN ODUs) and full wavelengths, in order to satisfy application requirements laid out in this program.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-malis-ccamp-fast-lsps-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-malis-ccamp-fast-lsps-00.txt' />
</reference>
