<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.asai-cross-domain-overlay'>
<front>
<title>Considerations on the AS-Level Application-Layer Traffic Optimization</title>

<author initials='H' surname='Asai' fullname='Hirochika Asai'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Esaki' fullname='Hiroshi Esaki'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Momose' fullname='Tsuyoshi Momose'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='June' day='3' year='2012' />

<abstract><t>Overlay routing technologies (a.k.a. peer-to-peer technologies) have been introduced to various distributed systems, such as content delivery networks and live media streaming systems.  However, these systems cannot always utilize optimal network resources from the viewpoint of layer 3 network providers and operators of layer 3 network providers have difficulties in controlling and optimizing the traffic of these systems because these systems construct their own networks (i.e., overlay networks) over the layer 3 network without taking into account layer 3 network's routing policies.  The ALTO Working Group has worked on application-layer traffic optimization to fill the gaps in routing policies between the layer 3 network and overlay networks by providing the underlay network topology and cost information to applications that build overlay networks.  However, since ASes are operated under different policies and cost metrics for application-layer traffic optimization are assumed to be autonomously configured by each AS, there are considerations in applying application-layer traffic optimization techniques to cross-domain (inter-AS) traffic.  This document summarizes general problems with cross-domain traffic of overlay networks and considerations on the AS-level application-layer traffic optimization from the viewpoint of inter-AS economics.  This document also discusses the conceivable approaches to solve the problems and considerations.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-asai-cross-domain-overlay-04' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-asai-cross-domain-overlay-04.txt' />
</reference>
