<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.brandenburg-avt-rtcp-for-idms'>
<front>
<title>RTCP XR Block Type for inter-destination media synchronization</title>

<author initials='H' surname='Stokking' fullname='Hans Stokking'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='O' surname='Deventer' fullname='Oskar van Deventer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='O' surname='Niamut' fullname='Omar Niamut'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='F' surname='Walraven' fullname='Fabian Walraven'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Brandenburg' fullname='Ray Brandenburg'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='I' surname='Vaishnavi' fullname='Ishan Vaishnavi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='September' day='24' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>This document specifies an RTCP XR Block Type for inter-destination media synchronization (IDMS). The RTCP Block Type is used to collect information on media play-out time of a specific RTP media stream, and to distribute a summary of the collected information. This information can be used to synchronize the play-out of media such as audio, video and/or subtitles among multiple devices.  This document also specifies the associated SDP parameter. The SDP parameter is used to signal the use of the RTCP XR block for inter- destination media synchronization.  Typical applications for inter-destination media synchronization are social TV, watching apart together and shared service control. Each of these applications has two or more geographically separated users watching a media stream on respective devices. RTCP-XR is intended as a signaling mechanism to enable various media synchronization algorithms amongst users. The presented RTCP-XR specification for IDMS is independent of the used synchronization algorithm.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-brandenburg-avt-rtcp-for-idms-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-brandenburg-avt-rtcp-for-idms-00.txt' />
</reference>
