<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-ccamp-mpls-tp-cp-framework'>
<front>
<title>MPLS-TP Control Plane Framework</title>

<author initials='L' surname='Andersson' fullname='Loa Andersson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Berger' fullname='Lou Berger'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Fang' fullname='Luyuan Fang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='N' surname='Bitar' fullname='Nabil Bitar'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Gray' fullname='Eric Gray'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Takacs' fullname='Attila Takacs'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Vigoureux' fullname='Martin Vigoureux'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Bellagamba' fullname='Elisa Bellagamba'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='7' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>The MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) supports static provisioning of transport paths via a Network Management System (NMS), and dynamic provisioning of transport paths via a control plane. This document provides the framework for MPLS-TP dynamic provisioning, and covers control plane addressing, routing, path computation, signaling, traffic engineering, and path recovery.  MPLS-TP uses GMPLS as the control plane for MPLS-TP LSPs.  MPLS-TP also uses the Pseudowire (PW) control plane for Pseudowires (PWs). Management plane functions are out of scope of this document.  This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and Pseudowire Emulation Edge-to-Edge (PWE3) architectures to support the capabilities and functionalities of a packet transport network as defined by the ITU-T.  This Informational Internet-Draft is aimed at achieving IETF Consensus before publication as an RFC and will be subject to an IETF Last Call.  [RFC Editor, please remove this note before publication as an RFC and insert the correct Streams Boilerplate to indicate that the published RFC has IETF consensus.]</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-ccamp-mpls-tp-cp-framework-05' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-ccamp-mpls-tp-cp-framework-05.txt' />
</reference>
