<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.bi-savi-problem'>
<front>
<title>Problem Statement of SAVI Beyond the First Hop</title>

<author initials='J' surname='Bi' fullname='Jun Bi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Liu' fullname='Bingyang Liu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='29' year='2012' />

<abstract><t>IETF Source Address Validation Improvements (SAVI) working group is chartered for source address validation within the first hop from the end hosts, i.e. preventing a node from spoofing the IP source address of another node in the same IP link.  Despite the drafts that are being actively standardized, the process of deployment on the Internet will take a long time, because the edge of the Internet is too huge.  Therefore some source address validation mechanisms implemented beyond the first hop (SAVI-BF) are needed to suppress source address spoofing inside the network.  So far, Ingress Filtering [BCP38]/[BCP84] is the best current practice for SAVI-BF. However Ingress Filtering may drop legitimate packets (false positive) or fail to recognize spoofing packets (false negative) in case of asymmetric routing, which is not rare under SAVI-BF scenario.  This document states the problems of Ingress Filtering under SAVI-BF scenario.  Then we discuss how to better utilize the routing information to better enforce SAVI-BF, in the case of link-state and distance-vector routing protocols respectively.  Challenges to SAVI-BF, such as equal-cost multi-path routing (ECMP), static-routing and local routing policy, fast reroute and inter-domain route aggregation are discussed.  We also observe that the incentive for Internet Service Providers (ISP) to deploy SAVI-BF differs from intra-domain scenario to inter-domain scenario, and incenting ISPs to deploy inter-domain SAVI is quite challenging.  Finally we discuss the philosophy in designing a SAVI-BF mechanism.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-bi-savi-problem-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-bi-savi-problem-00.txt' />
</reference>
