<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.varon-hrpc-methodology'>
<front>
<title>Human Rights Protocol Considerations Methodology</title>

<author initials='J' surname='Varon' fullname='Joana Varon'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='N' surname='Oever' fullname='Niels Oever'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Guarnieri' fullname='Claudio Guarnieri'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Scott' fullname='Will Scott'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Cath' fullname='Corinne Cath'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='December' day='4' year='2015' />

<abstract><t>This document presents steps undertaken for developing a methodology to map engineering concepts at the protocol level that may be related to promotion and protection of Human Rights, particularly the right to freedom of expression and association.  It aims to facilitate and build the work done by the Human Rights Protocol Considerations research group in the IRTF, as well as other authors within the IETF.  Exemplary work [RFC1984] [RFC6973] [RFC7258] has already been done in the IETF on privacy issues that should be considered when creating an Internet protocol.  But, beyond privacy considerations, concerns for freedom of expression and association were also a strong part of the world-view of the community involved in developing the first Internet protocols.  Indeed, promoting open, secure and reliable connectivity is essential for these rights.  But how are this concepts addressed in the protocol level?  Are there others?  This ID is intended to explain research work done so far and to explore possible methodological approaches to move further on exploring and exposing the relations between standards and protocols and the promotion and protection of the rights to freedom of expression and association.  Discussion on this draft at: hrpc@irtf.org // https://www.irtf.org/mailman/listinfo/hrpc</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-varon-hrpc-methodology-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-varon-hrpc-methodology-02.txt' />
</reference>
