<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-forces-protocol'>
<front>
<title>ForCES Protocol Specification</title>

<author initials='L' surname='Dong' fullname='Ligang Dong'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Doria' fullname='Avri Doria'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Gopal' fullname='Ram Gopal'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='HAAS' fullname='Robert  HAAS'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Salim' fullname='Jamal Hadi Salim'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Khosravi' fullname='Hormuzd Khosravi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Wang' fullname='Weiming Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='30' year='2008' />

<abstract><t>This document specifies the Forwarding and Control Element Separation (ForCES) protocol.  ForCES protocol is used for communications between Control Elements(CEs) and Forwarding Elements (FEs) in a ForCES Network Element (ForCES NE).  This specification is intended to meet the ForCES protocol requirements defined in RFC3654.  Besides the ForCES protocol, this specification also defines the requirements for the Transport Mapping Layer (TML).Authors  The participants in the ForCES Protocol Team, primary co-authors and co-editors, of this protocol specification, are:  Ligang Dong (Zhejiang Gongshang University), Avri Doria (Lulea University of Technology), Ram Gopal (Nokia), Robert Haas (IBM), Jamal Hadi Salim (Znyx), Hormuzd M Khosravi (Intel), and Weiming Wang (Zhejiang Gongshang University).  Special acknowledgement goes to Joel Halpern who has done extensive editing in support of congruence between the model and this protocol specification.  Without his participation and persistence, this specification might never have been completed.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-forces-protocol-18' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-forces-protocol-18.txt' />
</reference>
