<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-ipfix-export-per-sctp-stream'>
<front>
<title>IPFIX Export per SCTP Stream</title>

<author initials='B' surname='Claise' fullname='Benoit Claise'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='P' surname='Aitken' fullname='Paul Aitken'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Johnson' fullname='Andrew Johnson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Muenz' fullname='Gerhard Muenz'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='10' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>This document specifies an improvement to the Partial  Reliability extension of SCTP (PR-SCTP, Partial Reliability  Stream Control Transmission Protocol) export specified in  the IP Flow Information Export (IPFIX) specifications in  RFC5101.  This method offers several advantages such as the ability to  calculate Data Record losses for PR-SCTP, immediate export of  Template Withdrawal Messages, immediate reuse of Template IDs  within an SCTP stream, and reduced demands on the Collecting  Process.  Status of this Memo  This Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance  with the provisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.  Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet  Engineering Task Force (IETF), its areas, and its working  groups.  Note that other groups may also distribute working  documents as Internet-Drafts.  Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six  months and may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other  documents at any time.  It is inappropriate to use Internet-  Drafts as reference material or to cite them other than as "work  in progress."  The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed at  http://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt  The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed at  http://www.ietf.org/shadow.html  This Internet-Draft will expire on January 10th, 2010.  Copyright Notice  &lt;Claise, et. Al>  Expires January 10, 2010  [page 1]  Internet-Draft &lt;IPFIX Export per SCTP Stream>  July 2009  Copyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as the  document authors.  All rights reserved.  This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's Legal  Provisions Relating to IETF Documents in effect on the date of  publication of this document (http://trustee.ietf.org/license-  info).  Please review these documents carefully, as they  describe your rights and restrictions with respect to this  document.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-ipfix-export-per-sctp-stream-03' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-ipfix-export-per-sctp-stream-03.txt' />
</reference>
