<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-ccamp-lsp-dppm'>
<front>
<title>Label Switched Path (LSP) Dynamic Provisioning Performance Metrics in  Generalized MPLS Networks</title>

<author initials='W' surname='Sun' fullname='Weiqiang Sun'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Zhang' fullname='Guoying Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Gao' fullname='Jianhua Gao'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Xie' fullname='Guowu Xie'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Papneja' fullname='Rajiv Papneja'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Gu' fullname='Bin Gu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='X' surname='Wei' fullname='Xueqing Wei'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Otani' fullname='Tomohiro Otani'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Jing' fullname='Ruiquan Jing'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='9' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>Generalized Multi-Protocol Label Switching (GMPLS) is one of the most promising candidate technologies for future data transmission network.  GMPLS has been developed to control and operate different kinds of network elements, such as conventional routers, switches, Dense Wavelength Division Multiplexing (DWDM) systems, Add- Drop Multiplexers (ADMs), photonic cross-connects (PXCs), optical cross- connects (OXCs), etc.  Dynamic provisioning ability of these physically diverse devices differs from each other drastically.  At the same time, the need for dynamically provisioned connections is increasing because optical networks are being deployed in metro areas.  As different applications have varied requirements in the provisioning performance of optical networks, it is imperative to define standardized metrics and procedures such that the performance of networks and application needs can be mapped to each other.  This document provides a series of performance metrics to evaluate the dynamic LSP provisioning performance in GMPLS networks, specifically the dynamic LSP setup/release performance.  These metrics can depict the features of GMPLS networks in LSP dynamic provisioning.  They can also be used in operational networks for carriers to monitor the control plane performance in realtime.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-ccamp-lsp-dppm-06' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-ccamp-lsp-dppm-06.txt' />
</reference>
