<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.popovic-iprp'>
<front>
<title>iPRP: Parallel Redundancy Protocol for IP Networks</title>

<author initials='M' surname='Popovic' fullname='Miroslav Popovic'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Mohiuddin' fullname='Maaz Mohiuddin'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Boudec' fullname='Jean-Yves Le Boudec'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Tomozei' fullname='Dan-Cristian Tomozei'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='August' day='10' year='2015' />

<abstract><t>Reliable packet delivery within stringent delay-constraints is of paramount importance to industrial processes with hard real-time constraints, such as electrical grid monitoring. Because retransmission and coding techniques counteract the delay requirements, reliability is achieved through replication over multiple fail-independent paths. Existing solutions such as the parallel redundancy protocol (PRP) replicate all packets at the MAC layer over parallel paths. PRP works best in local area networks, e.g., sub-station networks. However, it is not viable for IP-layer wide-area networks which are key elements of emerging smart grids. Such a limitation on scalability, coupled with lack of security, and diagnostic inability, renders it unsuitable for reliable data- delivery in smart grids. To address this issue, a transport-layer design: IP parallel redundancy protocol (iPRP) is presented. Designing iPRP poses non-trivial challenges in the form of selective packet-replication, soft-state and multicast support. In addition to unicast, iPRP supports multicast, widely used in smart-grid networks. It replicates only time-critical UDP traffic. iPRP only requires a simple software installation on the end-devices. There are no other modifications needed to the existing monitoring application, end- device operating system or to the intermediate network devices. iPRP has a set of diagnostic tools for network debugging. With an implementation of iPRP in Linux, it is shown that iPRP supports multiple flows with minimal processing-and-delay overhead. It is publicly available and is currently being installed in the EPFL campus smart-grid.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-popovic-iprp-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-popovic-iprp-00.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-popovic-iprp-00.pdf' />
</reference>
