<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.irtf-icnrg-icniot'>
<front>
<title>Design Considerations for Applying ICN to IoT</title>

<author initials='R' surname='Ravindran' fullname='Ravi Ravindran'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Zhang' fullname='Yanyong Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Grieco' fullname='Luigi Grieco'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Lindgren' fullname='Anders Lindgren'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Burke' fullname='Jeff Burke'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Ahlgren' fullname='Bengt Ahlgren'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Azgin' fullname='Aytac Azgin'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='22' year='2018' />

<abstract><t>The Internet of Things (IoT) promises to connect billions of objects to the Internet.  After deploying many stand-alone IoT systems in different domains, the current trend is to develop a common, "thin waist" of protocols to enable a horizontally unified IoT architecture.  The objective of such an architecture is to make resource objects securely accessible to applications across organizations and domains.  Towards this goal, quite a few proposals have been made to build an application-layer based unified IoT platform on top of today's host-centric Internet.  However, there is a fundamental mismatch between the host-centric nature of today's Internet and the mostly information-centric nature of the IoT domain. To address this mismatch, the common set of protocols and network services offered by an information-centric networking (ICN) architecture can be leveraged to realize an ICN-based IoT (or ICN- IoT) architecture that can take advantage of the salient features of ICN such as naming, security, mobility, compute and efficient content and service delivery support offered by it.  In this draft, we summarize the general IoT demands, and ICN features that support these requirements, and then discuss the challenges to realize an ICN-based IoT framework.  Beyond this, the goal of this draft is not to offer any specific ICN-IoT architectural proposal.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-irtf-icnrg-icniot-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-irtf-icnrg-icniot-02.txt' />
</reference>
