<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.baba-iot-problems'>
<front>
<title>Problems in and among industries for the prompt realization of IoT and safety considerations</title>

<author initials='H' surname='BABA' fullname='Hiroyuki BABA'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Ishida' fullname='Yoshiki Ishida'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Amatsu' fullname='Takayuki Amatsu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='KUNITAKE' fullname='Koichi KUNITAKE'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Maeda' fullname='Kaoru Maeda'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='30' year='2017' />

<abstract><t>This document contains opinions gathered from enterprises engaging in the IoT business as stated in the preceding version hereof, and also examines the possibilities of new social problems in the IoT era. Recognition of the importance of information security has grown in step with the rising use of the Internet.  Closer examination reveals that the IoT era may see a new direct physical threat to users.  For instance, the situation at a smart house may lead it to judge that the owner has only temporarily stepped out, causing it to unlock the front door, which in turn makes it easier for thieves to enter. These kinds of scenarios may occur without identity fraud, hacking, and other means of compromising information security.  Therefore, for the purpose of this document, this issue shall be referred to as "IoT Safety" to distinguish it from Information Security.  We believe that it is necessary to deepen our understanding of these new IoT-related threats through discussion and ensure there are measures to address these threats in the future.  At the same time, we must also coordinate these measures with the solutions to the problems described in the previous version of this document.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-baba-iot-problems-04' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-baba-iot-problems-04.txt' />
</reference>
