<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.nieminen-core-service-discovery'>
<front>
<title>Configuration and service discovery of IPv6 capable sensors</title>

<author initials='J' surname='Nieminen' fullname='Johanna Nieminen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Patil' fullname='Basavaraj Patil'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Savolainen' fullname='Teemu Savolainen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Isomaki' fullname='Markus Isomaki'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Z' surname='Shelby' fullname='Zach Shelby'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Gomez' fullname='Carles Gomez'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='24' year='2011' />

<abstract><t>The number and type of Internet connected devices continues to grow rapidly.  Sensors are a new category of devices that are becoming Internet connected.  While sensors have existed for a long time, it is only now that we see sensors being capable of communicating via an IP stack.  Sensors are used in a multitude of industries and applications.  By enabling these devices to be Internet connected, they open up new vistas in terms of applications and uses.  Most sensors are generally small with minimal power and processing capabilities.  The ability to configure these devices is a challenge. However, in order to make the usage and deployment of Internet connected sensors easier, it is essential that there exist a well defined configuration, control, and service discovery mechanism. This document illustrates various use cases of sensors in different types of deployments and a solution for configuring and controlling them in addition to the ability for sensors and devices to discover services.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-nieminen-core-service-discovery-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-nieminen-core-service-discovery-00.txt' />
</reference>
