<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.kanugovi-intarea-mams-framework'>
<front>
<title>Multiple Access Management Services</title>

<author initials='S' surname='Kanugovi' fullname='Satish Kanugovi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='F' surname='Baboescu' fullname='Florin Baboescu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Zhu' fullname='Jing Zhu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Mueller' fullname='Julius Mueller'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Seo' fullname='SungHoon Seo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='September' day='4' year='2018' />

<abstract><t>In multiconnectivity scenarios the end-user devices can simultaneously connect to multiple networks based on different access technologies and network architectures like WiFi, LTE, DSL.  Both the quality of experience of the users and the overall network utilization and efficiency may be improved through a smart selection and combination of access and core network paths that can dynamically adapt to changing network conditions.  The document presents a unified problem statement and introduces a solution for managing multiconnectivity.  The solution has been developed based on the authors' experience in multiple standards bodies including the IETF and 3GPP and is not an Internet Standard.  It describes the requirements, solution principles and the architectural framework that ensures best performance and can be easily implemented in a wide variety of multiconnectivity deployments.  It specifies the the protocol multi-access management to 1) flexibly select the best combination of access and core network paths for uplink and downlink, as well as 2) determining the user plane treatment and traffic distribution over the selected links ensuring better network efficiency and enhanced application performance.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-kanugovi-intarea-mams-framework-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-kanugovi-intarea-mams-framework-02.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-kanugovi-intarea-mams-framework-02.pdf' />
</reference>
