<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.novak-bmwg-ipflow-meth'>
<front>
<title>IP Flow Information Accounting and Export Benchmarking Methodology</title>

<author initials='J' surname='Novak' fullname='Jan  Novak'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Claise' fullname='Benoit Claise'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='13' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>This document provides methodology and framework for quantifying performance of selective monitoring of IP flows on a network device and export of this information to a collector. It is based on the Architecture for IP Flow Information Export [RFC5470].  Status of this Memo  This Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with the provisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.  Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups.  Note that other groups may also distribute working documents as Internet- Drafts.  Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six months and may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at any time.  It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as reference material or to cite them other than as "work in progress."  The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed at http://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.  The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed at http://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.  This Internet-Draft will expire on January 1, 2010.  Copyright Notice  Copyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as the document authors.  All rights reserved.  This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's Legal Provisions Relating to IETF Documents in effect on the date of publication of this document (http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info). Please review these documents carefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respect to this document.  Novak  Expires January 1, 2010</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-novak-bmwg-ipflow-meth-03' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-novak-bmwg-ipflow-meth-03.txt' />
</reference>
