<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.zhang-ccamp-rwa-wson-routing-ospf'>
<front>
<title>OSPF Extensions in Support of Routing and Wavelength Assignment (RWA) in  Wavelength Switched Optical Networks (WSONs)</title>

<author initials='F' surname='Zhang' fullname='Fatai Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Bernstein' fullname='Greg Bernstein'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Lee' fullname='Young Lee'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Li' fullname='Dan Li'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Han' fullname='Jianrui Han'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='1' year='2009' />

<abstract><t>Wavelength switched optical networks (WSONs) are based on Wavelength Division Multiplexing (WDM) in which user traffic is carried by data channels of different optical wavelengths. In traditional WDM Networks, each wavelength path is statically configured. With the  deployment of Reconfigurable Optical Add-Drop Multiplexers (ROADMs), photonic cross-connects (PXCs), and tunable laser, WSONs have become more dynamic, and operators can flexibly set up wavelength paths to carry user traffic.  In WSONs where there are no or a limited number of switches capable of wavelength conversion paths must be set up subject to the "wavelength continuity" constraint. This leads to a path computation problem known as routing and wavelength assignment (RWA). In order to perform such computations, it is necessary to collect information about the available wavelengths within the network.  This document describes OSPF routing protocols extensions to support Wavelength Switched Optical Networks (WSON) under the control of Generalized MPLS (GMPLS).</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-zhang-ccamp-rwa-wson-routing-ospf-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zhang-ccamp-rwa-wson-routing-ospf-00.txt' />
</reference>
