<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.geng-rtgwg-cfn-dyncast-ps-usecase'>
<front>
<title>Dynamic-Anycast in Compute First Networking (CFN-Dyncast) Use Cases and Problem Statement</title>
<author initials='L' surname='Geng' fullname='Liang Geng'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='P' surname='Liu' fullname='Peng Liu'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='P' surname='Willis' fullname='Peter Willis'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2020' month='October' day='30' />
<abstract><t>Service providers are exploring the edge computing to achieve better response time, control over data and carbon energy saving by moving the computing services towards the edge of the network in scenarios of 5G MEC (Multi-access Edge Computing), virtualized central office, and others.  Providing services by sharing computing resources from multiple edges is emerging and becoming more and more useful for computationally intensive tasks.  The service nodes attached to multiple edges normally have two key features, service equivalency and service dynamism.  Ideally they should serve the service in a computational balanced way.  However lots of approaches dispatch the service in a static way, e.g., to the geographically closest edge, and they may cause unbalanced usage of computing resources at edges which further degrades user experience and system utilization.  This draft provides an overview of scenarios and problems associated.</t><t> Networking taking account of computing resource metrics as one of its top parameters is called Compute First Networking (CFN) in this document.  The document identifies several key areas which require more investigations in architecture and protocol to achieve the balanced computing and networking resource utilization among edges in CFN.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-geng-rtgwg-cfn-dyncast-ps-usecase-00'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-geng-rtgwg-cfn-dyncast-ps-usecase-00.txt'/>
</reference>
