<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.zulr-mpls-tp-linear-protection-switching'>
<front>
<title>Pre-standard Linear Protection Switching in MPLS-TP</title>

<author initials='H' surname='Helvoort' fullname='Huub van Helvoort'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Ryoo' fullname='Jeong-dong Ryoo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Z' surname='Haiyan' fullname='Zhang Haiyan'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='F' surname='Huang' fullname='Feng Huang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Li' fullname='Han Li'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='D&apos;Alessandro' fullname='Alessandro D&apos;Alessandro'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='February' day='12' year='2014' />

<abstract><t>The IETF Standards Track solution for MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS- TP) Linear Protection is provided in RFC 6378, draft-ietf-mpls-psc- updates and draft-ietf-mpls-tp-psc-itu.  This document describes the pre-standard implementation of MPLS-TP Linear Protection that has been deployed by several network operators using equipment from multiple vendors.  At the time of publication these pre-standard implementations were still in operation carrying live traffic.  The specified mechanism supports 1+1 unidirectional/bidirectional protection switching and 1:1 bidirectional protection switching.  It is purely supported by MPLS-TP data plane, and can work without any control plane.  [Editor's note] The followings are to be included in "Status of Memo":  This document is not an Internet Standards Track specification; it is published for informational purposes.  This is a contribution to the RFC Series, independently of any other RFC stream.  The RFC Editor has chosen to publish this document at its discretion and makes no statement about its value for implementation or deployment.  Documents approved for publication by the RFC Editor are not a candidate for any level of Internet Standard; see Section 2 of RFC 5741.  Information about the current status of this document, any errata, and how to provide feedback on it may be obtained at http://www.rfc- editor.org/info/rfcxxxx.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-zulr-mpls-tp-linear-protection-switching-11' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zulr-mpls-tp-linear-protection-switching-11.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zulr-mpls-tp-linear-protection-switching-11.pdf' />
</reference>
