<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.contreras-layered-sdn'>
<front>
<title>Cooperating Layered Architecture for Software Defined Networking (CLAS)</title>

<author initials='L' surname='Contreras' fullname='Luis Contreras'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Bernardos' fullname='Carlos Bernardos'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Lopez' fullname='Diego Lopez'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Boucadair' fullname='Mohamed Boucadair'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='P' surname='Iovanna' fullname='Paola Iovanna'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='November' day='22' year='2018' />

<abstract><t>Software Defined Networking adheres to the separation of the control plane from the data plane in the network nodes and its logical centralization on one or a set of control entities.  Most of the network and/or sevice intelligence is moved to these control entities.  Typically, such entity is seen as a compendium of interacting control functions in a vertical, tight integrated fashion.  The relocation of the control functions from a number of distributed network nodes to a logical central entity conceptually places together a number of control capabilities with different purposes.  As a consequence, the existing solutions do not provide a clear separation between transport control and services that relies upon transport capabilities.  This document describes an approach named Cooperating Layered Architecture for Software Defined Networking.  The idea behind that is to differentiate the control functions associated to transport from those related to services, in such a way that they can be provided and maintained independently, and can follow their own evolution path.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-contreras-layered-sdn-03' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-contreras-layered-sdn-03.txt' />
</reference>
