<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.jfaizan-mipv6-vhar'>
<front>
<title>Virtual Home Agent Reliability Protocol (VHAR)</title>

<author initials='H' surname='El-Rewini' fullname='Hesham El-Rewini'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Khalil' fullname='Mohamed  Khalil'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Faizan' fullname='Jahanzeb Faizan'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='April' day='12' year='2004' />

<abstract><t>Current specifications of Mobile IPv6 does not provide Home Agent Reliability in the home link. The aim of this draft is to introduce Virtual Home Agent Reliability Protocol as the solution. In this protocol multiple Home Agents coexist on the same home link and share the same Global IP address. Only one of them is active at a time and serves the Mobile Node. The Home Agent failure and failover mechanisms are completely transparent to the Mobile Node which is required for minimal service interruption time. This protocol does not introduce any new Mobile IPv6 message over the air interface and thus helps reducing the overall overhead. Current specifications of Mobile IPv6 does not provide Home Agent Reliability in the home link. The aim of this draft is to introduce Virtual Home Agent Reliability Protocol as the solution. In this protocol multiple Home Agents coexist on the same home link and share the same Global IP address. Only one of them is active at a time and serves the Mobile Node. The Home Agent failure and failover mechanisms are completely transparent to the Mobile Node which is required for minimal service interruption time. This protocol does not introduce any new Mobile IPv6 message over the air interface and thus helps reducing the overall overhead.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-jfaizan-mipv6-vhar-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-jfaizan-mipv6-vhar-02.txt' />
</reference>
