<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.kong-sdnrg-routing-optimization-sdn-in-dc'>
<front>
<title>Routing Optimization with SDN in Data Center Networks</title>

<author initials='Q' surname='Kong' fullname='Qian Kong'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Gao' fullname='Tao Gao'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Wang' fullname='Dajiang Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Z' surname='Wang' fullname='Zhenyu Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Wang' fullname='Jiayu Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Guo' fullname='Bingli Guo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Huang' fullname='Shanguo Huang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='October' day='7' year='2019' />

<abstract><t>With the open and standard programmatic interface and the flexibility of controlling network, Software Defined Network (SDN) can obviously simplify and integrate operation and business support systems. As a consequence, to satisfy the rising switching demand in the data center network, it is a good option to adopt SDN technology. In addition, current architecture of data center network is far from ideality, which results in the low utilization rate in bandwidth resource. For example, mice flow cannot be well effectively served in the conventional Wavelength Division Multiplexing (WDM) optical network with at least 50GHz spectrum interval. From a data center network perspective, it is necessary to further improve the resource utilization efficiency and the flexibility of coping with different traffic.  This document described an optical data center interconnect, which comprises both the fixed and flexible grid transceivers. A traffic monitor is implemented in the SDN-based data center network to evaluate the coming traffic demands and allocate appropriate spectrum for the request. For instance, mice flow can be served by fixed grid transceivers, well the elephant flows can be transmitted by the flexi-grid transceiver using multiple subcarriers to form a superchannel. Thus, spectrum efficiency is optimized and bandwidth utilization is improved dramatically.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-kong-sdnrg-routing-optimization-sdn-in-dc-07' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-kong-sdnrg-routing-optimization-sdn-in-dc-07.txt' />
</reference>
