<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.li-nmrg-control-slicing'>
<front>
<title>Centralized Control and Distributed Function Slicing for Fast Connection Establishment and Fault Recovery in Optical Networks</title>
<author initials='L' surname='Xin' fullname='Li Xin'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='L' surname='Zhang' fullname='Lu Zhang'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='J' surname='Wei' fullname='Jianghua Wei'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='Y' surname='Tang' fullname='Ying Tang'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='S' surname='Huang' fullname='Shanguo Huang'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2020' month='November' day='02' />
<abstract><t>Optical networks which support a large number of emerging applications, such as 5G, Cloud Computing, Big Data, Internet of things, autonomous driving, etc., play an increasingly important role in the current world. All the time spectrum resources in optical networks have been treated equally. All spectrum resources form a resource pool which is allocated to applications bit by bit until it is all used up. Although this pattern reduces the complexity of resource maintenance, it has poor flexibility and high operation complexity for different types of applications. This draft proposes a framework of centralized control and distributed function slicing for fast connection establishment and fault recovery in optical networks. The proposed framework divides all spectrum resources into four functional areas, i.e., optical channel area, fault recovery area, resource pool area, and the reserved functional area. A functional area is responsible for a specific network function. This framework improves the flexibility of optical networks and can achieve fast connection establishment and fault recovery for the request with a highest service level.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-li-nmrg-control-slicing-00'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-li-nmrg-control-slicing-00.txt'/>
</reference>
