<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-pce-pcep-service-aware'>
<front>
<title>Extensions to the Path Computation Element Communication Protocol (PCEP) to compute service aware Label Switched Path (LSP).</title>

<author initials='D' surname='Dhody' fullname='Dhruv Dhody'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Q' surname='Wu' fullname='Qin Wu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='V' surname='Manral' fullname='Vishwas Manral'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Z' surname='Ali' fullname='Zafar Ali'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='K' surname='Kumaki' fullname='Kenji Kumaki'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='September' day='22' year='2016' />

<abstract><t>In certain networks, such as, but not limited to, financial information networks (e.g. stock market data providers), network performance criteria (e.g. latency) are becoming as critical to data path selection as other metrics and constraints.  These metrics are associated with the Service Level Agreement (SLA) between customers and service providers.  The link bandwidth utilization (the total bandwidth of a link in actual use for the forwarding) is another important factor to consider during path computation.  IGP Traffic Engineering (TE) Metric extensions describe mechanisms with which network performance information is distributed via OSPF and IS-IS respectively.  The Path Computation Element Communication Protocol (PCEP) provides mechanisms for Path Computation Elements (PCEs) to perform path computations in response to Path Computation Clients (PCCs) requests.  This document describes the extension to PCEP to carry latency, delay variation, packet loss and link bandwidth utilization as constraints for end to end path computation.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-pce-pcep-service-aware-13' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-pce-pcep-service-aware-13.txt' />
</reference>
