<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.zhang-ccamp-transport-ctrlnorth-yang'>
<front>
<title>YANG Models for the Northbound Interface of a Transport Network Controller: Requirements, Functions, and a List of YANG Models</title>

<author initials='X' surname='Zhang' fullname='Xian Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Jing' fullname='Ruiquan Jing'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Jian' fullname='Wei Jian'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Ryoo' fullname='Jeong-dong Ryoo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Xu' fullname='Yunbin Xu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='King' fullname='Daniel King'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='6' year='2016' />

<abstract><t>A transport network is a server-layer network designed to provide connectivity services for a client-layer network to carry the client traffic opaquely across the server-layer network resources.  A transport network may be constructed from equipment utilizing any of a number of different transport technologies such as the evolving optical transport infrastructure (Synchronous Optical Networking (SONET) / Synchronous Digital Hierarchy (SDH) and Optical Transport Network (OTN)) or packet transport as epitomized by the MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP).  All transport networks have high benchmarks for reliability and operational simplicity.  This suggests a common, technology- independent management/control paradigm that can be extended to represent and configure specific technology attributes.  This document describes the requirements facing transport networks in order to provide open interfaces for resource programmability and control/management automation. A list of existing and additional YANG models is provided to fulfill the functional requirements.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-zhang-ccamp-transport-ctrlnorth-yang-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zhang-ccamp-transport-ctrlnorth-yang-00.txt' />
</reference>
