<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.martocci-roll-commercial-routing-reqs'>
<front>
<title>Commercial Routing Requirements in Low Power and Lossy Networks</title>

<author initials='J' surname='Martocci' fullname='Jerry  Martocci'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Humpal' fullname='Ted Humpal'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='N' surname='Riou' fullname='Nicolas Riou'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Williamsson' fullname='Jon Williamsson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='14' year='2008' />

<abstract><t>The ROLL Working Group was recently chartered by the IETF to define routing characteristics for low power embedded devices.  ROLL would like to serve the Industrial, Commercial, Home and Urban markets.  Pursuant to this effort, this document defines the functional and cost requirements for installing integrated facility management systems in commercial facilities.  The routing requirements for commercial building applications are presented in this document.  Commercial buildings have been fitted with pneumatic and subsequently electronic communication pathways connecting  Martocci  Expires January 14, 2009  [page  1]  Internet-Draft  draft-martocci-roll-commercial-routing-reqs July 2008  sensors to their controllers for over one hundred years.  Recent economic and technical advances in wireless communication allows facilities to increasingly utilize a wireless solution in lieu of a wired solution; thereby reducing installation costs yet maintaining highly reliant communication.  Wireless solutions will be adapted from their existing wired counterparts in many of the building applications including, but not limited to HVAC, lighting, security, fire, and elevator products. These devices will be developed to reduce installation costs; while increasing installation and retrofit flexibility.  Sensing devices may be battery or mains powered.  Actuators and area controllers will be mains powered.  To meet the cost target, these devices must have a total installed cost below that of the traditional wired alternative; yet maintain reliability on par with wired devices.  The total installed cost includes the infrastructure, product, installation, commissioning, labor and operational costs of the device over its 30 year lifespan. Except for special circumstances such as flexible installation (e.g. airports) or cosmetics (e.g. museums, there is nothing compelling about installing wireless solutions inside a building unless it can be accomplished below the cost of a wired installation.  This document will define the requirements necessary for wireless technology to displace wired infrastructure and meet this objective.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-martocci-roll-commercial-routing-reqs-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-martocci-roll-commercial-routing-reqs-00.txt' />
<format type='PDF'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-martocci-roll-commercial-routing-reqs-00.pdf' />
</reference>
