<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.tschofenig-lwig-tls-minimal'>
<front>
<title>A Hitchhiker's Guide to the (Datagram) Transport Layer Security Protocol for Smart Objects and Constrained Node Networks</title>

<author initials='H' surname='Tschofenig' fullname='Hannes Tschofenig'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Kumar' fullname='Sandeep Kumar'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Keoh' fullname='Sye Keoh'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='5' year='2013' />

<abstract><t>Transport Layer Security (TLS) is a widely used security protocol that offers communication security services at the transport layer. The initial design of TLS was focused on the protection of applications running on top of the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP), and was a good match for securing the Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP).  Subsequent standardization efforts lead to the publication of the Datagram Transport Layer Security (DTLS) protocol, which allows the re-use of the TLS security functionality and the payloads to be exchanged on top of the User Datagram Protocol (UDP).  With the work on the Constrained Application Protocol (CoAP), as a specialized web transfer protocol for use with constrained nodes and constrained networks, DTLS is a preferred communication security protocol.  Smart objects are constrained in various ways (e.g., CPU, memory, power consumption) and these limitations may impose restrictions on the protocol stack such a device runs. This document only looks at the security part of that protocol stacks and the ability to customize TLS/DTLS. To offer input for implementers and system architects this document illustrates the costs and benefits of various TLS/DTLS features for use with smart objects and constraint node networks.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-tschofenig-lwig-tls-minimal-03' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-tschofenig-lwig-tls-minimal-03.txt' />
</reference>
