<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.zhang-hebeu-hma-dsin'>
<front>
<title>Hypernetwork Model and Architecture for Deep Space Information Networks</title>

<author initials='L' surname='Zhang' fullname='Long Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='l' surname='luqieranya@163.com' fullname='luqieranya@163.com'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Cao' fullname='Wenjing Cao'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Huang' fullname='Wei Huang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='Y' surname='Ding' fullname='Yan Ding'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='April' day='21' year='2014' />

<abstract><t>The increasing world-wide demands in deep space scientific missions, such as Lunar, Mars and other Planetary Exploration, along with the rapidly growing advances in space communication technologies have triggered the vision of so called future Deep Space Information Networks (DSINs). The coined DSIN paradigm is envisioned to be an integrated high speed self-organizing hypernetwork consisting of the terrestrial ground-based information networks and the outer space- based entities to provide maximum network capacity. In this document, the problem of network infrastructure and architecture for DSINs is investigated. Taking into account the major challenges or characteristics affecting link, networking, transport, and security design of DSINs, this document employs hypergraph theory to construct network infrastructure and node architecture of space optical switching, and further presents a five-layered hypernetwork model of DSINs to enhance network connectivity. Combining with the benefits in interconnection and interoperability of heterogeneous challenged networks, brought by the well-known Delay-and Disruption-Tolerant Networking (DTN) architecture, this document proposes a novel architecture of DSINs from two levels including Layered Protocol Stack and Management Plane. The proposed architecture preliminarily achieves the basic concepts and the relevant mechanisms of wisdom network, and the performance and quality of service (QoS) of DSINs are thereby improved.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-zhang-hebeu-hma-dsin-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zhang-hebeu-hma-dsin-00.txt' />
</reference>
