<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.irtf-icnrg-videostreaming'>
<front>
<title>Adaptive Video Streaming over ICN</title>

<author initials='c' surname='cedric.westphal@huawei.com' fullname='cedric.westphal@huawei.com'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Lederer' fullname='Stefan Lederer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Mueller' fullname='Christopher Mueller'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Detti' fullname='Andrea Detti'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Corujo' fullname='Daniel Corujo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Wang' fullname='Jianping Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Montpetit' fullname='Marie-Jose Montpetit'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='N' surname='Murray' fullname='Niall Murray'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='C' surname='Timmerer' fullname='Christian Timmerer'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Posch' fullname='Daniel Posch'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='a' surname='aytav.azgin' fullname='aytav.azgin'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='(Will)' fullname='Shucheng LIU (Will)'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='April' day='28' year='2016' />

<abstract><t>This document considers the consequences of moving the underlying network architecture from the current Internet to an Information- Centric Network (ICN) architecture on video distribution. As most of the traffic in future networks is expected to be video, we consider how to modify the existing video streaming mechanisms. Several important topics related to video distribution over ICN are presented, covering a wide range of scenarios: we look at how to evolve DASH to work over ICN, and leverage the recent ISO/IEC Moving Picture Experts Group (MPEG) Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (DASH) standard; we consider layered encoding over ICN; Peer-to-Peer (P2P) mechanisms introduce distinct requirements for video and we look at how to adapt PPSP for ICN; Internet Protocol Television (IPTV) adds delay constraints, and this will create more stringent requirements over ICN as well. As part of the discussion on video, we discuss Digital Rights Management (DRM) in ICN. Finally, in addition to considering how existing mechanisms would be impacted by ICN, this document lists some research issues to design ICN specific video streaming mechanisms.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-irtf-icnrg-videostreaming-08' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-irtf-icnrg-videostreaming-08.txt' />
</reference>
