<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-kitten-rfc5653bis'>
<front>
<title>Generic Security Service API Version 2: Java Bindings Update</title>

<author initials='M' surname='Upadhyay' fullname='Mayank Upadhyay'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Malkani' fullname='Seema Malkani'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Weijun' fullname='Wang Weijun'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='February' day='8' year='2018' />

<abstract><t>The Generic Security Services Application Program Interface (GSS-API) offers application programmers uniform access to security services atop a variety of underlying cryptographic mechanisms.  This document updates the Java bindings for the GSS-API that are specified in "Generic Security Service API Version 2 : Java Bindings Update" (RFC 5653).  This document obsoletes RFC 5653 by adding a new output token field to the GSSException class so that when the initSecContext or acceptSecContext methods of the GSSContext class fails it has a chance to emit an error token which can be sent to the peer for debugging or informational purpose.  The stream-based GSSContext methods are also removed in this version.  The GSS-API is described at a language-independent conceptual level in "Generic Security Service Application Program Interface Version 2, Update 1" (RFC 2743).  The GSS-API allows a caller application to authenticate a principal identity, to delegate rights to a peer, and to apply security services such as confidentiality and integrity on a per-message basis.  Examples of security mechanisms defined for GSS- API are "The Simple Public-Key GSS-API Mechanism" (RFC 2025) and "The Kerberos Version 5 Generic Security Service Application Program Interface (GSS-API) Mechanism: Version 2" (RFC 4121).</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-kitten-rfc5653bis-07' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-kitten-rfc5653bis-07.txt' />
</reference>
