<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.king-teas-applicability-actn-slicing'>
<front>
<title>Applicability of Abstraction and Control of Traffic Engineered Networks (ACTN) to Network Slicing</title>
<author initials='D' surname='King' fullname='Daniel King'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='J' surname='Drake' fullname='John Drake'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='H' surname='Zheng' fullname='Haomian Zheng'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='A' surname='Farrel' fullname='Adrian Farrel'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2021' month='March' day='31' />
<abstract><t>Network abstraction is a technique that can be applied to a network domain.  It utilizes a set of policies to select network resources and obtain a view of potential connectivity across the network.</t><t> Network slicing is an approach to network operations that builds on the concept of network abstraction to provide programmability, flexibility, and modularity.  It may use techniques such as Software Defined Networking (SDN) and Network Function Virtualization (NFV) to create multiple logical or virtual networks, each tailored for a set of services that share the same set of requirements.</t><t> Abstraction and Control of Traffic Engineered Networks (ACTN) is described in RFC 8453.  It defines an SDN-based architecture that relies on the concept of network and service abstraction to detach network and service control from the underlying data plane.</t><t> This document outlines the applicability of ACTN to network slicing in a Traffic Engineering (TE) network that utilizes IETF technology. It also identifies the features of network slicing not currently within the scope of ACTN, and indicates where ACTN might be extended.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-king-teas-applicability-actn-slicing-10'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-king-teas-applicability-actn-slicing-10.txt'/>
</reference>
