<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.shalunov-tana-problem-statement'>
<front>
<title>Transport for Advanced Networking Applications (TANA) Problem Statement</title>

<author initials='S' surname='Shalunov' fullname='Stanislav Shalunov'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='July' day='14' year='2008' />

<abstract><t>The IETF P2PI workshop conducted in the end of May 2008 at MIT in Boston has identified a number of potential documents for the IETF to work on.  One is a transport protocol with congestion control mechanism that enables an advanced networking application to minimize the extra delay it induces in the bottleneck while implementing an end-to-end version of scavenger service.  At least one such protocol has now been implemented by a major peer-to-peer application and deployed in the wild with favorable results.  Another is a document that addresses community concerns about the use of multiple transport connections by peer-to-peer applications, both when these connections run to the same peer and to different peers.  These two items appear to fall within the Transport area, but not within the charter of any existing working group.  It is not obvious what WG's charter could be naturally extended to encompass these two items.  The TANA BoF is held to explore the problem space, gauge the interest in the problems within the Transport area, and to see if the community and the area directors believe that it makes sense to form a TANA working group within the Transport area chartered to work on  1.  standardizing end-to-end congestion control that enables advanced  application to minimize the delay they introduce into the network  and a protocol using it and  2.  a document describing the current practice of peer-to-peer apps'  use of multiple transport connections and recommendations in this  space.1.  Requirements notation</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-shalunov-tana-problem-statement-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-shalunov-tana-problem-statement-01.txt' />
</reference>
