<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.huang-alto-mowie-for-network-aware-app'>
<front>
<title>MoWIE for Network Aware Application</title>
<author initials='C' surname='Xiong' fullname='Chunshan Xiong'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='Y' surname='Zhang' fullname='Yunfei Zhang'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='R' surname='Yang' fullname='Richard Yang'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='G' surname='Li' fullname='Gang Li'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='Y' surname='Lei' fullname='Yixue Lei'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='Y' surname='Han' fullname='Yunbo Han'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2021' month='July' day='12' />
<abstract><t>With the quick deployment of 5G networks in the world, cloud based interactive services such as clouding gaming have gained substantial attention and are regarded as potential killer applications.  To ensure users' quality of experience (QoE), a cloud interactive service may require not only high bandwidth (e.g., high-resolution media transmission) but also low delay (e.g., low latency and low lagging).  However, the bandwidth and delay experienced by a mobile and wireless user can be dynamic, as a function of many factors, and unhandled changes can substantially compromise users' QoE.  In this document, we investigate network-aware applications (NAA), which realize cloud based interactive services with improved QoE, by efficient utilization of Mobile and Wireless Information Exposure (MoWIE) . In particular, this document demonstrates, through realistic evaluations, that mobile network information such as MCS (Modulation and Coding Scheme) can effectively expose the dynamicity of the underlying network and can be made available to applications through MoWIE; using such information, the applications can then adapt key control knobs such as media codec scheme, encapsulation and application logical function to minimize QoE deduction.  Based on the evaluations, we discuss how MoWIE can be a systematic extension of the ALTO protocol, to expose more lower-layer and finer grain network dynamics.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-huang-alto-mowie-for-network-aware-app-03'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-huang-alto-mowie-for-network-aware-app-03.txt'/>
</reference>
