<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.irtf-icnrg-icn-lte-4g'>
<front>
<title>Experimental Scenarios of ICN Integration in 4G Mobile Networks</title>
<author initials='P' surname='suthar' fullname='Prakash suthar'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='M' surname='Stolic' fullname='Milan Stolic'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='A' surname='Jangam' fullname='Anil Jangam'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='D' surname='Trossen' fullname='Dirk Trossen'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2022' month='January' day='28' />
<abstract><t>4G mobile network uses IP-based transport for the control plane to establish the data session at the user plane for the actual data delivery.  In the existing architecture, IP-based unicast is used for the delivery of multimedia content to a mobile terminal, where each user is receiving a separate stream from the server.  From a bandwidth and routing perspective, this approach is inefficient. Evolved multimedia broadcast and multicast service (eMBMS) provides capabilities for delivering contents to multiple users simultaneously, but its deployment is very limited or at an experimental stage due to numerous challenges.  The focus of this draft is to list the options for use of Information centric technology (ICN) in 4G mobile networks and elaborate the experimental setups for its further evaluation.  The experimental setups discussed provide for using ICN either natively or with existing mobility protocol stack.  With further investigations based on the listed experiments, ICN with its inherent capabilities such as, network- layer multicast, anchorless mobility, security, and optimized data delivery using local caching at the edge may provide a viable alternative to IP transport in 4G mobile networks.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-irtf-icnrg-icn-lte-4g-11'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-irtf-icnrg-icn-lte-4g-11.txt'/>
</reference>
