<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.carrozzo-pce-pcep-route-price'>
<front>
<title>PCEP extensions for the computation of route offers with price</title>

<author initials='G' surname='Carrozzo' fullname='Gino Carrozzo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Bernini' fullname='Giacomo Bernini'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Landi' fullname='Giada Landi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='March' day='4' year='2012' />

<abstract><t>The PCE defined in RFC4655 is a functional entity generally confined in the control plane to elaborate explicit optimal routes with related costs to be installed as [G]MPLS tunnels/LSPs.  The resulting route cost(s)/metric(s) are Traffic Engineering indicators used by the network administrator (carrier) to optimize the usage of its network resources.  In this document a framework for the usage of PCE in cooperation with the Network Service and Business Plane (NSBP) is proposed, along with related PCEP extensions.  The NSBP invokes this extended PCE (service PCE) to trigger the computation of network service offers with related price information.  The price of a network connectivity service generally depends on strategic factors, but it could also be influenced by the amount of mobilized network resources (along the route), the ingress/egress interfaces/PoPs, etc.  Therefore, it could be provided by an extended service-PCE as an additional route information.  This document focuses on the extensions to the PCEP protocol in support of the computation of route prices for intra- and inter- domain network connectivity services.  Mechanisms for elaborating and retrieving price information in the PCE are vendor-specific and out of the scope of this document.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-carrozzo-pce-pcep-route-price-00' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-carrozzo-pce-pcep-route-price-00.txt' />
</reference>
