<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-bess-evpn-irb-mcast'>
<front>
<title>EVPN Optimized Inter-Subnet Multicast (OISM) Forwarding</title>
<author initials='W' surname='Lin' fullname='Wen Lin'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='Z' surname='Zhang' fullname='Zhaohui Zhang'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='J' surname='Drake' fullname='John Drake'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='E' surname='Rosen' fullname='Eric Rosen'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='J' surname='Rabadan' fullname='Jorge Rabadan'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='A' surname='Sajassi' fullname='Ali Sajassi'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2021' month='May' day='24' />
<abstract><t>Ethernet VPN (EVPN) provides a service that allows a single Local Area Network (LAN), comprising a single IP subnet, to be divided into multiple &quot;segments&quot;.  Each segment may be located at a different site, and the segments are interconnected by an IP or MPLS backbone. Intra-subnet traffic (either unicast or multicast) always appears to the endusers to be bridged, even when it is actually carried over the IP or MPLS backbone.  When a single &quot;tenant&quot; owns multiple such LANs, EVPN also allows IP unicast traffic to be routed between those LANs. This document specifies new procedures that allow inter-subnet IP multicast traffic to be routed among the LANs of a given tenant, while still making intra-subnet IP multicast traffic appear to be bridged.  These procedures can provide optimal routing of the inter- subnet multicast traffic, and do not require any such traffic to leave a given router and then reenter that same router.  These procedures also accommodate IP multicast traffic that needs to travel to or from systems that are outside the EVPN domain.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-bess-evpn-irb-mcast-06'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-bess-evpn-irb-mcast-06.txt'/>
</reference>
