<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.otis-dkim-tpa-label'>
<front>
<title>DKIM Third-Party Authorization Label</title>

<author initials='t' surname='messages' fullname='transmitting messages'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Otis' fullname='Douglas Otis'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Black' fullname='Daniel Black'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='August' day='10' year='2010' />

<abstract><t>A third party authorization label (TPA-Label) is a DNS-based extension for DKIM ADSP records that allows domains in the From header field to authorize acceptable third-party signatures.  This approach allows autonomous and unilateral authorizations for third- party domains using scalable, individual DNS transactions.  The extended scope of DKIM signing practice assertions introduced here supplants transparent authorization schemes that are more difficult to administer.  Alternatives for facilitating third-party authorizations currently necessitate coordination between two or more domains to synchronously set up selector/key DNS records, DNS zone delegations, and/or a regular exchange of public/private keys.  Checking TPA-Label Resource Records for signing practices might occur infrequently when a message is not compliant with restrictive ADSP practices, where an Author Domain Signature is either missing or invalid.  When a third-party signature is found, TPA-Label Resource Record transactions offer an efficient means for Author Domains to authorize specific third-party signing domains.  Recipients are afforded a method to determine whether authorization exists in situations where other modes of authorization are impractical.  TPA- Label Resource Records permit Author Domains a means to influence message handling selectively, for messages otherwise lacking valid Author Domain signatures.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-otis-dkim-tpa-label-06' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-otis-dkim-tpa-label-06.txt' />
</reference>
