<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-netconf-restconf-client-server'>
<front>
<title>RESTCONF Client and Server Models</title>
<author initials='K' surname='Watsen' fullname='Kent Watsen'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2022' month='May' day='24' />
<abstract><t>This document defines two YANG modules, one module to configure a RESTCONF client and the other module to configure a RESTCONF server. Both modules support the TLS transport protocol with both standard RESTCONF and RESTCONF Call Home connections.</t><t> Editorial Note (To be removed by RFC Editor)</t><t> This draft contains placeholder values that need to be replaced with finalized values at the time of publication.  This note summarizes all of the substitutions that are needed.  No other RFC Editor instructions are specified elsewhere in this document.</t><t> Artwork in this document contains shorthand references to drafts in progress.  Please apply the following replacements (note: not all may be present):</t><t> *  AAAA --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-crypto- types</t><t> *  BBBB --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-trust- anchors</t><t> *  CCCC --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-keystore</t><t> *  DDDD --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-tcp-client- server</t><t> *  EEEE --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-ssh-client- server</t><t> *  FFFF --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-tls-client- server</t><t> *  GGGG --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-http- client-server</t><t> *  HHHH --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-netconf- client-server</t><t> *  IIII --&gt; the assigned RFC value for this draft</t><t> Artwork in this document contains placeholder values for the date of publication of this draft.  Please apply the following replacement:</t><t> *  2022-05-24 --&gt; the publication date of this draft</t><t> The following Appendix section is to be removed prior to publication:</t><t> *  Appendix A.  Change Log</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-netconf-restconf-client-server-26'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-netconf-restconf-client-server-26.txt'/>
</reference>
