<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-dots-signal-call-home'>
<front>
<title>Distributed Denial-of-Service Open Threat Signaling (DOTS) Signal Channel Call Home</title>
<author initials='T' surname='Reddy.K' fullname='Tirumaleswar Reddy.K'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='M' surname='Boucadair' fullname='Mohamed Boucadair'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='J' surname='Shallow' fullname='Jon Shallow'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2021' month='May' day='27' />
<abstract><t>This document specifies the DOTS signal channel Call Home, which enables a Call Home DOTS server to initiate a secure connection to a Call Home DOTS client, and to receive attack traffic information from the Call Home DOTS client.  The Call Home DOTS server in turn uses the attack traffic information to identify compromised devices launching outgoing DDoS attacks and take appropriate mitigation action(s).</t><t> The DOTS signal channel Call Home is not specific to home networks; the solution targets any deployment in which it is required to block DDoS attack traffic closer to the source(s) of a DDoS attack.</t><t> Editorial Note (To be removed by RFC Editor)</t><t> Please update these statements within the document with the RFC number to be assigned to this document:</t><t> o  &quot;This version of this YANG module is part of RFC XXXX;&quot;</t><t> o  &quot;RFC XXXX: Distributed Denial-of-Service Open Threat Signaling (DOTS) Signal Channel Call Home&quot;;</t><t> o  &quot;| [RFCXXXX] |&quot;</t><t> o  reference: RFC XXXX</t><t> Please update this statement with the RFC number to be assigned to the following documents:</t><t> o  &quot;RFC YYYY: Distributed Denial-of-Service Open Threat Signaling (DOTS) Signal Channel Specification&quot; (used to be I-D.ietf-dots- rfc8782-bis)</t><t> Please update TBD/TBA statements with the assignments made by IANA to DOTS Signal Channel Call Home.</t><t> Also, please update the &quot;revision&quot; date of the YANG module.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-dots-signal-call-home-14'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-dots-signal-call-home-14.txt'/>
</reference>
