<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.johnson-h350-directory-serv'>
<front>
<title>H.350 Directory Services</title>

<author initials='T' surname='Johnson' fullname='Tyler Johnson'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Okubo' fullname='Sakae Okubo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Campos' fullname='Simão Ferraz de  Campos'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='May' day='12' year='2004' />

<abstract><t>The International Telecommunications Union Standardization Sector (ITU-T) has created the H.350 series of Recommendations that specify directory services architectures in support of multimedia conferencing protocols. The goal of the architecture is to 'directory enable' multimedia conferencing so that these services can leverage existing identity management and enterprise directories. A particular goal is to enable an enterprise or service provider to maintain a canonical source of users and their multimedia conferencing systems, so that multiple call servers from multiple vendors, supporting multiple protocols, can all access the same data store. Because SIP is an IETF standard, the contents of H.350 and H.350.4 are made available via this document to the IETF community. This document contains the entire normative text of ITU-T Recommendations H.350 and H.350.4 in sections 4 and 5, respectively. The remaining sections are included only in this document, not in the ITU-T version. Specific differences between this text and the original include: 1. This text contains a Security Considerations section (section 9) not found in the original. 2. This text includes an additional reference to RFC 2798 which defines inetOrgPerson and userSMIMECertificate. 3. This text does not contain the non-normative appendices found in the original. These appendices include implementation considerations and graphics for system implementers.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-johnson-h350-directory-serv-02' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-johnson-h350-directory-serv-02.txt' />
</reference>
