<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-mpls-tp-ring-protection'>
<front>
<title>Applicability of MPLS-TP Linear Protection for Ring Topologies</title>

<author initials='Y' surname='Weingarten' fullname='Yaacov Weingarten'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='S' surname='Bryant' fullname='Stewart Bryant'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Ceccarelli' fullname='Daniele Ceccarelli'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Caviglia' fullname='Diego Caviglia'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='F' surname='Fondelli' fullname='Francesco Fondelli'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='M' surname='Corsi' fullname='Marco Corsi'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='W' surname='Bo' fullname='Wu Bo'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='X' surname='Dai' fullname='Xuehui Dai'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='April' day='30' year='2013' />

<abstract><t>This document presents an applicability of existing MPLS protection mechanisms, both local and end-to-end, to Multi-Protocol Label Switching Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) in ring topologies.  This document does not propose any new mechanisms or protocols. Protection on rings offers a number of opportunities for optimization as the protection choices are starkly limited (all traffic traveling one way around a ring can only be switched to travel the other way on the ring), but also suffers from some complications caused by the limitations of the topology.  Requirements for MPLS-TP protection especially for protection in ring topologies are discussed in "Requirements of an MPLS Transport Profile" (RFC 5654) and "MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) Survivability Framework" (RFC 6372).  This document shows how MPLS-TP linear protection as defined in RFC 6378 can be applied to single ring topologies, discusses how most of the requirements are met, and describes scenarios in which the function provided by applying linear protection in a ring topology falls short of some of the requirements.  This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunications Union Telecommunications Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and PWE3 architectures to support the capabilities and functionalities of a packet transport network as defined by the ITU-T.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-mpls-tp-ring-protection-06' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-mpls-tp-ring-protection-06.txt' />
</reference>
