<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.zhang-icnrg-icniot'>
<front>
<title>Design Considerations for Applying ICN to IoT</title>

<author initials='Y' surname='Zhang' fullname='Yanyong Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='D' surname='Raychadhuri' fullname='Dipankar Raychadhuri'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='L' surname='Grieco' fullname='Luigi Grieco'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Baccelli' fullname='Emmanuel Baccelli'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Burke' fullname='Jeff Burke'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='R' surname='Ravindran' fullname='Ravi Ravindran'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='G' surname='Wang' fullname='Guoqiang Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='A' surname='Lindgren' fullname='Anders Lindgren'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='B' surname='Ahlgren' fullname='Bengt Ahlgren'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='O' surname='Schelen' fullname='Olov Schelen'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='June' day='26' year='2017' />

<abstract><t>The Internet of Things (IoT) promises to connect billions of objects to the Internet.  After deploying many stand-alone IoT systems in different domains, the current trend is to develop a common, "thin waist" of protocols over a horizontal unified, defragmented IoT architecture.  Such an architecture will make objects accessible to applications across organizations and domains.  Towards this goal, quite a few proposals have been made to build an application-layer based unified IoT platform on top of today's host-centric Internet. However, there is a fundamental mismatch between the host-centric nature of todays Internet and mostly information-centric nature of the IoT system.  To address this mismatch, an information-centric network (ICN) architecture can provide a common set of protocols and services, called 'ICN-IoT', which can be used to build IoT platforms. ICN-IoT leverages the salient features of ICN, and thus provides naming, security, mobility support,scalability, and efficient content and service delivery.  This draft summarizes general IoT demands, and covers the challenges and design considerations ICN faces to realize a ICN-IoT framework based on ICN architecture.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-zhang-icnrg-icniot-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zhang-icnrg-icniot-01.txt' />
</reference>
