<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.sun-nmrg-hybrid-switching'>
<front>
<title>Resource Allocation Model for Hybrid Switching Networks</title>
<author initials='W' surname='Sun' fullname='Weiqiang Sun'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='J' surname='Shao' fullname='Junyi Shao'>
<organization />
</author>
<author initials='W' surname='Hu' fullname='Weisheng Hu'>
<organization />
</author>
<date year='2022' month='May' day='29' />
<abstract><t>The fast increase in traffic volumn within and outside Datacenters is placing an unprecendented challenge on the underline network, in both the capacity it can provide, and the way it delivers traffic.  When a large portion of network traffic is contributed by large flows, providing high capacity and slow to change optical circuit switching along side fine-granular packet services may potentially improve network utility and reduce both CAPEX and OpEX.  This gives rise to the concept of hybrid switching - a paradigm that seeks to make the best of packet and circuit switching.</t><t> However, the full potential of hybrid switching networks (HSNs) can only be realized when such a network is optimally designed and operated, in the sense that &quot;an appropriate amount of resource is used to handle an appropriate amount of traffic in both switching planes.&quot;  The resource allocation problem in HSNs is in fact complex ineractions between three components: resource allocation between the two switching planes, traffic partitioning between the two switching planes, and the overall cost or performance constraints.</t><t> In this memo, we explore the challenges of planning and operating hybrid switching networks, with a particular focus on the resource allocation problem, and provide a high-level model that may guide resource allocation in future hybrid switching networks.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-sun-nmrg-hybrid-switching-05'/>
<format type='TXT' target='https://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-sun-nmrg-hybrid-switching-05.txt'/>
</reference>
