<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.zhaoyl-ccamp-p2mp-requirement-flexi-grid'>
<front>
<title>Requirements for Supporting P2MP in Flexi-Grid Networks</title>

<author initials='Y' surname='Zhao' fullname='Yongli Zhao'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='X' surname='Yu' fullname='Xiaosong Yu'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Zhang' fullname='Jie Zhang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='J' surname='Wang' fullname='Jiayu Wang'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='X' surname='Lin' fullname='Xuefeng Lin'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='8' year='2013' />

<abstract><t>Multicasting over WDM optical networks has enabled many popular Point-to-Multipoint (P2MP) applications, such as video conference, interactive distance learning, replicated database, distributed computing, and so on.  However, on the one hand, the low-rate multicasting traffic demands cannot make full use of the capacity of the entire wavelength, and on the other hand, new services such as data center migration and cloud applications need higher transmission rates and higher spectrum efficiency.  Flexi-grid network is an effective solution to address the problem of transmission rate and spectrum utilization.  It overcomes the fixed grid constraint of Wavelength Swithched Optical Network (WSON) by using advanced technologies such as coherent detection and Bandwidth Variable- Wavelength Selective Switches (BV-WSS).  Therefore, it is essential to exploit multicasting over flexi-grid networks.  This document covers the requirements for supporting P2MP over flexi-grid infrastructure.  Specifically, the scope of requirements listed in this document covers the functionality that should be supported by the control plane.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-zhaoyl-ccamp-p2mp-requirement-flexi-grid-01' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-zhaoyl-ccamp-p2mp-requirement-flexi-grid-01.txt' />
</reference>
