<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='I-D.ietf-sipclf-problem-statement'>
<front>
<title>The Common Log Format (CLF) for the Session Initiation Protocol (SIP): Framework and Information Model</title>

<author initials='V' surname='Gurbani' fullname='Vijay Gurbani'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='E' surname='Burger' fullname='Eric Burger'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='T' surname='Anjali' fullname='Tricha Anjali'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='H' surname='Abdelnur' fullname='Humberto Abdelnur'>
    <organization />
</author>

<author initials='O' surname='Festor' fullname='Olivier Festor'>
    <organization />
</author>

<date month='January' day='3' year='2013' />

<abstract><t>Well-known web servers such as Apache and web proxies like Squid support event logging using a common log format.  The logs produced using these de-facto standard formats are invaluable to system administrators for trouble-shooting a server and tool writers to craft tools that mine the log files and produce reports and trends. Furthermore, these log files can also be used to train anomaly detection systems and feed events into a security event management system.  The Session Initiation Protocol (SIP) does not have a common log format, and as a result, each server supports a distinct log format that makes it unnecessarily complex to produce tools to do trend analysis and security detection.  This document describes a framework, including requirements and analysis of existing approaches, and specifies an information model for development of a SIP common log file format that can be used uniformly by user agents, proxies, registrars, redirect servers as well as back-to-back user agents.</t></abstract>

</front>

<seriesInfo name='Internet-Draft' value='draft-ietf-sipclf-problem-statement-13' />
<format type='TXT'
        target='http://www.ietf.org/internet-drafts/draft-ietf-sipclf-problem-statement-13.txt' />
</reference>
