<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference  anchor='RFC6941' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6941'>
<front>
<title>MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) Security Framework</title>
<author initials='L.' surname='Fang' fullname='L. Fang' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='B.' surname='Niven-Jenkins' fullname='B. Niven-Jenkins' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='S.' surname='Mansfield' fullname='S. Mansfield' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='R.' surname='Graveman' fullname='R. Graveman' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<date year='2013' month='April' />
<abstract><t>This document provides a security framework for the MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP).  MPLS-TP extends MPLS technologies and introduces new Operations, Administration, and Maintenance (OAM) capabilities, a transport-oriented path protection mechanism, and strong emphasis on static provisioning supported by network management systems.  This document addresses the security aspects relevant in the context of MPLS-TP specifically.  It describes potential security threats as well as mitigation procedures related to MPLS-TP networks and to MPLS-TP interconnection to other MPLS and GMPLS networks.  This document is built on RFC 5920 (&quot;Security Framework for MPLS and GMPLS Networks&quot;) by providing additional security considerations that are applicable to the MPLS-TP extensions.  All the security considerations from RFC 5920 are assumed to apply.</t><t>This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and Pseudowire Emulation Edge-to-Edge (PWE3) architectures to support the capabilities and functionality of a packet transport network.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='6941'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC6941'/>
</reference>
