<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference  anchor='RFC6372' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6372'>
<front>
<title>MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) Survivability Framework</title>
<author initials='N.' surname='Sprecher' fullname='N. Sprecher' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='A.' surname='Farrel' fullname='A. Farrel' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<date year='2011' month='September' />
<abstract><t>Network survivability is the ability of a network to recover traffic delivery following failure or degradation of network resources.  Survivability is critical for the delivery of guaranteed network services, such as those subject to strict Service Level Agreements (SLAs) that place maximum bounds on the length of time that services may be degraded or unavailable.</t><t>The Transport Profile of Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS-TP) is a packet-based transport technology based on the MPLS data plane that reuses many aspects of the MPLS management and control planes.</t><t>This document comprises a framework for the provision of survivability in an MPLS-TP network; it describes recovery elements, types, methods, and topological considerations.  To enable data-plane recovery, survivability may be supported by the control plane, management plane, and by Operations, Administration, and Maintenance (OAM) functions. This document describes mechanisms for recovering MPLS-TP Label Switched Paths (LSPs).  A detailed description of pseudowire recovery in MPLS-TP networks is beyond the scope of this document.</t><t>This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and Pseudowire Emulation Edge-to-Edge (PWE3) architectures to support the capabilities and functionalities of a packet-based transport network as defined by the ITU-T.  </t><t>This document is not an Internet Standards Track specification; it is published for informational purposes.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='6372'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC6372'/>
</reference>
