<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference  anchor='RFC8415' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc8415'>
<front>
<title>Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol for IPv6 (DHCPv6)</title>
<author initials='T.' surname='Mrugalski' fullname='T. Mrugalski'><organization /></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Siodelski' fullname='M. Siodelski'><organization /></author>
<author initials='B.' surname='Volz' fullname='B. Volz'><organization /></author>
<author initials='A.' surname='Yourtchenko' fullname='A. Yourtchenko'><organization /></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Richardson' fullname='M. Richardson'><organization /></author>
<author initials='S.' surname='Jiang' fullname='S. Jiang'><organization /></author>
<author initials='T.' surname='Lemon' fullname='T. Lemon'><organization /></author>
<author initials='T.' surname='Winters' fullname='T. Winters'><organization /></author>
<date year='2018' month='November' />
<abstract><t>This document describes the Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol for IPv6 (DHCPv6): an extensible mechanism for configuring nodes with network configuration parameters, IP addresses, and prefixes. Parameters can be provided statelessly, or in combination with stateful assignment of one or more IPv6 addresses and/or IPv6 prefixes.  DHCPv6 can operate either in place of or in addition to stateless address autoconfiguration (SLAAC).</t><t>This document updates the text from RFC 3315 (the original DHCPv6 specification) and incorporates prefix delegation (RFC 3633), stateless DHCPv6 (RFC 3736), an option to specify an upper bound for how long a client should wait before refreshing information (RFC 4242), a mechanism for throttling DHCPv6 clients when DHCPv6 service is not available (RFC 7083), and relay agent handling of unknown messages (RFC 7283).  In addition, this document clarifies the interactions between models of operation (RFC 7550).  As such, this document obsoletes RFC 3315, RFC 3633, RFC 3736, RFC 4242, RFC 7083, RFC 7283, and RFC 7550.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='8415'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC8415'/>
</reference>
