<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference  anchor='RFC7933' target='https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc7933'>
<front>
<title>Adaptive Video Streaming over Information-Centric Networking (ICN)</title>
<author initials='C.' surname='Westphal' fullname='C. Westphal' role='editor'><organization /></author>
<author initials='S.' surname='Lederer' fullname='S. Lederer'><organization /></author>
<author initials='D.' surname='Posch' fullname='D. Posch'><organization /></author>
<author initials='C.' surname='Timmerer' fullname='C. Timmerer'><organization /></author>
<author initials='A.' surname='Azgin' fullname='A. Azgin'><organization /></author>
<author initials='W.' surname='Liu' fullname='W. Liu'><organization /></author>
<author initials='C.' surname='Mueller' fullname='C. Mueller'><organization /></author>
<author initials='A.' surname='Detti' fullname='A. Detti'><organization /></author>
<author initials='D.' surname='Corujo' fullname='D. Corujo'><organization /></author>
<author initials='J.' surname='Wang' fullname='J. Wang'><organization /></author>
<author initials='M.' surname='Montpetit' fullname='M. Montpetit'><organization /></author>
<author initials='N.' surname='Murray' fullname='N. Murray'><organization /></author>
<date year='2016' month='August' />
<abstract><t>This document considers the consequences of moving the underlying network architecture from the current Internet to an Information- Centric Networking (ICN) architecture on video distribution.  As most of the traffic in future networks is expected to be video, we consider how to modify the existing video streaming mechanisms. Several important topics related to video distribution over ICN are presented.  The wide range of scenarios covered includes the following: evolving Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP (DASH) to work over ICN and leverage the recent ISO/IEC Moving Picture Experts Group (MPEG) standard, layering encoding over ICN, introducing distinct requirements for video using Peer-to-Peer (P2P) mechanisms, adapting the Peer-to-Peer Streaming Protocol (PPSP) for ICN, creating more stringent requirements over ICN because of delay constraints added by Internet Protocol Television (IPTV), and managing digital rights in ICN.  Finally, in addition to considering how existing mechanisms would be impacted by ICN, this document lists some research issues to design ICN-specific video streaming mechanisms.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='7933'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC7933'/>
</reference>
